<doc>
  <legacy_id>2481</legacy_id>
  <name>angle</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the angle of {<i>graphic</i> | <i>image</i>} to <i>angleInDegrees</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <graphic/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Appearance &amp; Positioning</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="revRotatePoly">revRotatePoly Command</command>
    <property tag="arcAngle">arcAngle Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="2.0"></changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies the starting angle of an arc or the rotation angle of a <keyword tag="regular">regular polygon</keyword> or <keyword tag="image">image</keyword>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the angle of graphic "Triangle" to 180</example>
    <example>set the angle of image ID 45902 to it</example>
    <example>set the angle of graphic myGraphic to the angle of myGraphic + 5</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>angle</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to create an arc shape, or to turn a <keyword tag="regular">regular polygon</keyword> or <keyword tag="image">image</keyword> object.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>angle</b> of a <keyword tag="graphic">graphic</keyword> or <i>image</i> is an <keyword tag="integer">integer</keyword> between zero and 360.</p><p/><p>By default, the <b>angle</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> of a newly created <keyword tag="graphic">graphic</keyword> or <keyword tag="image">image</keyword> is zero.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>If you specify an <i>angleInDegrees</i> greater than 360, the <b>angle</b> is set to the number you specify mod 360.</p><p/><p>A regular polygon can be rotated between zero and 360. Increasing the <i>angleInDegrees</i> rotates the polygon clockwise. You can specify the <b>angle</b> of a <keyword tag="graphic">graphic</keyword> that is not a <keyword tag="regular">regular polygon</keyword>, but it has no effect on the <glossary tag="graphic">graphic's</glossary> appearance.</p><p/><p>An image can be rotated between zero and 360. Increasing the <i>angleInDegrees</i> rotates the <keyword tag="image">image</keyword> counterclockwise. Unlike the <command tag="rotate">rotate</command> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary>, the <b>angle</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> affects only the screen display of the <keyword tag="image">image</keyword>, not the actual picture data in it. Changing an <glossary tag="image">image's</glossary> <b>angle</b> does not change the <property tag="imageData">imageData</property> of the <keyword tag="image">image</keyword>. Repeated changes to the <b>angle</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary>, unlike repeated uses of the <command tag="rotate">rotate</command> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary>, do not degrade the <glossary tag="image">image's</glossary> quality. The <command tag="rotate">rotate</command> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> cannot be used on a <glossary tag="referenced control">referenced image</glossary>, but the <b>angle</b> of a <glossary tag="referenced control">referenced image</glossary> can be set.</p><p/><p>By default, oval graphics display their entire arc from zero to 360, forming a complete oval. You can use the <b>angle</b> and <property tag="arcAngle">arcAngle</property> <property tag="properties">properties</property> to specify a portion of the oval to be displayed. The <b>angle</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> determines the starting point of the arc. Zero is at the right edge, 3 o'clock. Increasing the <b>angle</b> moves the starting point counter-clockwise around the arc. (The direction of rotation for an arc is opposite the direction of rotation for a polygon.) For example, if the <b>angle</b> is 90, the arc starts at the top edge of the graphic's rectangle, 12 o'clock.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> For an oval, the <b>angle</b> is the same as the <property tag="startAngle">startAngle</property>. Changing one changes the other.</p><p/><p><b>Changes:</b></p><p>The ability to set the <b>angle</b> of an <keyword tag="image">image</keyword> was introduced in version 2.0. In previous versions, the <b>angle</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> applied only to <glossary tag="graphic">graphics</glossary>.</p>
  </description>
</doc>