<doc>	<legacy_id>1362</legacy_id>	<name>backgroundBehavior</name>	<type>property</type>	<syntax>		<example>set the backgroundBehavior of <i>group</i> to {true | false}</example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>		<synonym>bgBehavior</synonym>	</synonyms>	<summary>Specifies whether a group behaves as a background and come after it's card on the message path.</summary>	<examples><example>set the backgroundBehavior of group 1 to false</example><example>set the backgroundBehavior of the last group to true</example><example><p>if the backgroundBehavior of group &quot;backgroundObjects&quot; is true then</p><p> -- do something</p><p>end if</p></example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="1.1">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version="4.6.4">Changed.</changed>	</history>	<objects>		<group/>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>		<ios/>		<android/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<server/>		<web/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>		<category>Objects &amp; Messages</category>	</classification>	<references>		<command tag="place">place Command</command>		<command tag="send">send Command</command>		<property tag="backgroundIDs">backgroundIDs Property</property>		<property tag="backgroundNames">backgroundNames Property</property>		<property tag="dynamicPaths">dynamicPaths Property</property>		<property tag="HCAddressing">HCAddressing Property</property>		<message tag="preOpenBackground">preOpenBackground Message</message>		<message tag="openBackground">openBackground Message</message>		<message tag="closeBackground">closeBackground Message</message>		<control_st tag="pass">pass Control Structure</control_st>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use the <b>backgroundBehavior</b> property to make groups behave like backgrounds and to automatically place groups on newly created cards.</overview>		<parameters>		</parameters>	<value>The <b>backgroundBehavior</b> of a group is true or false.<p></p><p>By default, the <b>backgroundBehavior</b> property of newly created groups is set to false.</p></value>	<comments>Only top-level groups may be background groups; an attempt to set the <b>backgroundBehavior</b> of a nested group to true throws an error.<p></p><p>A background group differs from a normal group in the following ways:</p><p>  * The group's script is placed behind the card in the message path for any message not originating from a control within it.</p><p>  * The group can be referred to using the 'background' chunk.</p><p>  * The card on which the group is placed receives <message tag="preOpenBackground">preOpenBackground</message>/<message tag="openBackground">openBackground</message>/<message tag="closeBackground">closeBackground</message> messages (these messages occur instead of <message tag="preOpenControl">preOpenControl</message>/<message tag="openControl">openControl</message>/<message tag="closeControl">closeControl</message> being sent to the group itself).</p><p>  * The group can be placed onto multiple cards.</p><p>  * If the group is placed on 'this card' at the time a new card is created, it is automatically placed onto the new (empty) card.</p><p></p><p>A background group is also a shared group. This means that when the <b>backgroundBehavior</b> is set to true, the <property tag="sharedBehavior">sharedBehavior</property> is also set to true (if it is not already).</p><p></p><p></p><note>Setting the <b>backgroundBehavior</b> of a group to false does not affect the <property tag="sharedBehavior">sharedBehavior</property> property, in particular the latter is not be set to false until it is explicitly done so.</note><p></p><p></p><note>Only groups whose <b>backgroundBehavior</b> is true appear in the list reported by the <property tag="backgroundIDs">backgroundNames</property> and <property tag="backgroundIDs">backgroundIDs</property> properties.</note><p></p><p></p><note>If a stack created in a version of LiveCode earlier than 1.1 is opened in 1.1 or later, the <b>backgroundBehavior</b> of all its groups is set to true by default. This also applies to imported HyperCard stacks.</note></comments>	</description></doc>