<doc>
  <legacy_id>2084</legacy_id>
  <name>blendLevel</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the blendLevel of <i>control</i> to <i>levelNumber</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Images  Multimedia</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <keyword tag="transparent">transparent Keyword</keyword>
    <property tag="opaque">opaque Property</property>
    <property tag="ink">ink Property</property>
    <property tag="alphaData">alphaData Property</property>
    <keyword tag="blend">blend Keyword</keyword>
    <property tag="outerGlow">outerGlow Property</property>
    <property tag="dropShadow">dropShadow Property</property>
    <property tag="innerShadow">innerShadow Property</property>
    <property tag="innerGlow">innerGlow Property</property>
    <property tag="colorOverlay">colorOverlay Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="2.7"></changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies the degree of transparency of an object</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the blendLevel of image 3 to 100</example>
    <example>set the blendLevel of field "Test" to the blendLevel of field "Test" - 1</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>blendLevel</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to allow <glossary tag="object">objects</glossary> underneath an object to show through partially or completely.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>blendLevel</b> of an object is an <keyword tag="integer">integer</keyword> between zero and 100.</p><p>By default, the <b>blendLevel</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> of newly created <glossary tag="image">objects</glossary> is set to 0.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>If an object's <b>blendLevel</b> is zero, the object is fully opaque. If the <b>blendLevel</b> is 100, the object is fully transparent. Values between zero and 100 indicate levels of partial translucency.</p><p/><p><code/><img src="202651"/> <b>Tip:</b><code/> The blendLevel setting of a stack obeys lock and unlock screen. In particular, if the screen is unlocked with a visual effect, the blendlevel of the stack will be interpolated between its new and old values during the action of the lifetime of the effect.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> In previous versions of LiveCode setting the blendLevel of an image would automatically set the ink to blend. This no longer happens and the blendLevel applies regardless of the setting of the ink. For backwards compatibility, when a pre-2.7 stackfile is imported, all images with the blendLevel set and ink set to blend will be converted to have the ink 'blendSrcOver' and the same blendLevel setting.</p><p/><p><code/><img src="202653"/> <b>Important!</b><code/> Setting the <i>blendLevel</i> of a stack is only supported on systems which support alpha-blended windows. This is currently MacOS X, Windows 2000 or later and Linux (with a composite window manager (such as Beryl))</p>
  </description>
</doc>