<doc>	<legacy_id></legacy_id>	<name>centerRect</name>	<type>property</type>	<syntax>		<example>set the centerRect[angle] of <i>image</i> to <i>left</i>,<i>top</i>,<i>right</i>,<i>bottom</i></example>		<example>get the [effective] centerRect[angle] of <i>image</i></example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Specifies a region of pixels that should be stretched when the image is stretched.</summary>	<examples><example>set the centerRect of image "buttonImage" to 20,20,45,200</example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="6.7">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version=""></changed>		<experimental version=""></experimental>		<nonexperimental version=""></nonexperimental>	</history>	<objects>		<image/>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>		<ios/>		<android/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<server/>		<web/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>		<category>Appearance &amp; Positioning</category>	</classification>	<references>		<property tag="rectangle">rectangle Property</property>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use to <b>centerRect </b>property to specifies a region of pixels that should be stretched when the image is stretched.</overview>		<parameters><parameter><name>image</name><description>A reference or expression that evaluate to an image reference.</description></parameter><parameter><name>rect</name><description>Empty or a comma delimited list of 4 integers representing the left,top,right,bottom of the rectangle being specified. By default, the centerRect property is empty.</description></parameter>		</parameters>	<value>The <b>centerRect</b> property return a comma delimited list of integers representing the top, left, right and bottom of the centerRect. By default, the <b>centerRect</b> property of an image is empty.</value>	<comments>If empty, then the property has no effect. <p></p><p>If the centerRect is set to a rectangle, then it is interpreted as relative to the source image rect (i.e. 0, 0, the formattedWidth of image, the formattedHeight of image) and it specifies a region of pixels that should be stretched when the image is stretched. In particular, the centerRect is stretched in both x and y directions, the corners outside of the centerRect are not stretched and the sides are stretched horizontally or vertically only depending on orientation.</p><p></p><p>The centerRect is useful for images being used as backgrounds to buttons as it allows a single image to be used to specify the borders and center stretching area.</p></comments>	</description></doc>