<doc>
	<legacy_id></legacy_id>
	<name>cursorMovement</name>
	<type>property</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>set the cursorMovement of field to {visual | logical | empty}</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Sets the mechanism for moving the cursor in fields containing both left-to-right and right-to-left text.</summary>

	<examples>
<example><p>set the cursorMovement of field "example" to "visual"</p></example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="7.0">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		
		<experimental version=""></experimental>
		<nonexperimental version=""></nonexperimental>
	</history>

	<objects>
		<field/>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<server/>
		<web/>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category></category>
		<category></category>
		<category></category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<property tag="textDirection">textDirection property</property>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>cursorMovement</b> property to set the mechanism that is to be used for moving the cursor in a field.</overview>

		<parameters>
<parameter>
<name>mechanism</name>
<description>The mechanism to be used used for moving the cursor in a field</description> 
<options title="">
<option>
<item>visual</item>
<description>moves the cursor in visual order</description>
</option>
<option>
<item>logical</item>
<description>moves the cursor to the next character in logical (reading) order</description>
</option>
<option>
<item>empty</item>
<description>moves the cursor using the default behavior on the current platform</description>
</option>
</options>
</parameter>		</parameters>

	<value></value>
	<comments><p>The <b>cursorMovement</b> property sets the mechanism that is to be used for moving the cursor in fields containing both left-to-right and right-to-left text.</p><p></p><p>The "visual" cursor movement mechanism moves the cursor in visual order, i.e pressing left will always move the cursor one position to the left. This is the default cursor movement on OS X.</p><p></p><p>The "logical" cursor movement moves the cursor to the next character in logical (reading) order when the left arrow is pressed and to the previous logical character when the right arrow is pressed. This is the default cursor movement on Windows.</p><p></p><p>Setting the <b>cursorMovement</b> property to empty indicates that the engine should use the default behaviour for the platform that it is being run on.</p></comments>
	</description>
</doc>