<doc>
  <legacy_id>2235</legacy_id>
  <name>defaultCursor</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the defaultCursor to<i> imageID</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <global/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>User Interaction</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <property tag="lockCursor">lockCursor Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.0">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="3.5"></changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies the <keyword tag="default">default</keyword> shape of the <property tag="cursor">cursor</property>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the defaultCursor to arrow</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>defaultCursor</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to change the <property tag="cursor">cursor</property> used when the <glossary tag="Browse tool">Browse tool</glossary> is being used from a hand to some other <property tag="cursor">cursor</property> shape.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>defaultCursor</b> is the <property tag="ID">ID</property> of an <keyword tag="image">image</keyword> to use for a <property tag="cursor">cursor</property>. </p><p/><p>LiveCode looks for the specified image in the following order:</p><p/><p>1) The stack of the current object's <property tag="behavior">behavior</property> (if applicable)</p><p>2) The stack of the owner of the current object's <property tag="behavior">behavior</property> (if applicable)</p><p> ...</p><p>n) The stack of the current object's stack's <property tag="behavior">behavior</property> (if applicable)</p><p>A) The current object's stack</p><p>B) The current object's stack's mainstack (if a substack)</p><p>C) The current object's stack's mainstacks substacks</p><p>D) The list of open stacks, in order they were loaded</p><p/><p><img src="202651"/> <b>Tip:</b> LiveCode includes several built-in <glossary tag="cursor">cursors</glossary> whose names you can use in place of their image IDs. The built-in cursors are described in the entry for the <property tag="cursor">cursor</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>If the <b>lockCursor</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is set to false, the <property tag="cursor">cursor</property> changes shape automatically as the mouse moves. (For example, the <property tag="cursor">cursor</property> normally turns into an arrow over a <keyword tag="menu">menu</keyword>, an I-beam over an editable <keyword tag="field">field</keyword>, and so on.) The <b>defaultCursor</b> is the shape used automatically when the <glossary tag="mouse pointer">mouse pointer</glossary> is in a stack window, but not in an editable <keyword tag="field">field</keyword>.</p><p/><p><b>Changes:</b></p><p>The order in which LiveCode searches for cursors was changed in version 3.5. Previously, the current stack was searched first, followed by the list of open stacks.</p>
  </description>
</doc>