<doc>
  <legacy_id>1605</legacy_id>
  <name>dontUseQT</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the dontUseQT to {true | false}</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <global/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Images  Multimedia</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="answer effect">answer effect Command</command>
    <function tag="QTVersion">QTVersion Function</function>
    <function tag="recordCompressionTypes">recordCompressionTypes Function</function>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="6.7.6">1.1</changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Disables the ability to use <glossary tag="QuickTime">QuickTime</glossary>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the dontUseQT to true</example>
    <example>if the platform is "Win32" then set the dontUseQT to true</example>
    <example>if the platform is "Win32" then set the dontUseQT of player "winPlayer" to true</example>
    <example>if the platform is "MacOS" then set the dontUseQT of player "osxPlayer" to false</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>dontUseQT</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to test operation of a <object tag="stack">stack</object> using the built-in MCI video on <glossary tag="Windows">Windows systems</glossary>, or to use built-in visual effects rather than <glossary tag="QuickTime">QuickTime</glossary> effects.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>dontUseQT</b> is true or false.</p><p/><p>By default, the <b>dontUseQT</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is set to false.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>If you have already used QuickTime during the current session, setting the <b>dontUseQT</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to true has no effect, because the code for LiveCode to use <glossary tag="QuickTime">QuickTime</glossary> is already <glossary tag="loaded into memory">loaded into memory</glossary> and will continue to be used until you quit the application.</p><p/><p>The following actions cause QuickTime to be loaded into memory:</p><p>        * Displaying a player object</p><p>        * Playing an audio clip or video clip</p><p>        * Recording sound using the <b>record sound</b> command</p><p>        * Using the <b>recordFormats</b> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st> or the <command tag="answer record">answer record</command> command</p><p>        * Using a visual effect with <b>visual effect</b>, <command tag="show">show</command>, <command tag="hide">hide</command>, or unlock screen</p><p>        * Using the answer effect <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> or <function tag="QTEffects">QTEffects</function> function</p><p>        * Using the <b>QTVersion</b> function</p><p/><p><img src="202651"/> <b>Tip:</b> It may take LiveCode a second or two to load the code needed to use QuickTime, depending on the machine speed. Since this code is only loaded into memory once per session, you can speed up the first occurrence of an action listed above by calling the QTVersion func during otherwise dead time--for example, during startup of your application--to preload QuickTime.</p><p/><p>The setting of this property has no effect on Unix systems.</p><p/><p>On OSX systems, the default value of this property is true if the OSX version is greater or equal to 10.8, and false otherwise. If the <b>dontUseQT</b> is true on a <glossary tag="Mac OS">Mac OS system</glossary>,it plays movies and sounds using the AVFoundation framework.</p><p/><p>On Windows, if this property is true then the setting of a player's <property tag="alwaysBuffer">alwaysBuffer property</property> will have no effect. Moreover, you can set the <b>dontUseQT</b> property for a player object. Just make sure you do so before setting the filename property of the player. The default value of this property of a player object is false on Windows, and true on OSX.
  </p>
  </description>
</doc>