<doc>
  <legacy_id>3496</legacy_id>
  <name>dragImage</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the dragImage to {empty | <i>imageID</i> }</example>
    <example>get the dragImage</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <global/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <message tag="dragEnd">dragEnd Message</message>
    <property tag="dragImageOffset">dragImageOffset Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.9">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="3.5"></changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Reports the id of an image that should be used to represent the drag operation.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>on dragStart</p><p>  set the dragImage to the id of image "Drag Image" of me</p><p>end dragStart</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>The <b>dragImage</b> property specifies the id of an image used to represent a drag operation. The property is set by the source application in a <message tag="dragStart">dragStart</message> handler.</p><p/><p>The image is only looked up after completion of the <message tag="dragStart">dragStart</message> handler in which it is set and so the image must persist for the lifetime of the operation. Typically, a control will want to use a pre-existing image object, or create a temporary object in <message tag="dragStart">dragStart</message> that it deletes when it receives <message tag="dragEnd">dragEnd</message>.</p><p/><p>LiveCode looks for the specified image in the following order:</p><p/><p>1) The stack of the current object's <property tag="behavior">behavior</property> (if applicable)</p><p>2) The stack of the owner of the current object's <property tag="behavior">behavior</property> (if applicable)</p><p> ...</p><p>n) The stack of the current object's stack's <property tag="behavior">behavior</property> (if applicable)</p><p>A) The current object's stack</p><p>B) The current object's stack's mainstack (if a substack)</p><p>C) The current object's stack's mainstacks substacks</p><p>D) The list of open stacks, in order they were loaded</p><p/><p><b>Changes:</b></p><p>The order in which LiveCode searches for drag images was changed in version 3.5. Previously, the current stack was searched first, followed by the list of open stacks.</p>
  </description>
</doc>