<doc>
  <legacy_id>2329</legacy_id>
  <name>formatForPrinting</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the formatForPrinting of <i>stack</i> to {true | false}</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <stack/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Printing</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="answer printer">answer printer Command</command>
    <property tag="pageHeights">pageHeights Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <windows/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies whether font layout is done using printer <glossary tag="font">fonts</glossary> or screen <glossary tag="font">fonts</glossary>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the formatForPrinting of stack "Print Template" to true</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>formatForPrinting</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to improve printout appearance on <glossary tag="Windows">Windows systems</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>formatForPrinting</b> of a <object tag="stack">stack</object> is true or false.</p><p/><p>By default, the <b>formatForPrinting</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> of newly created <function tag="stacks">stacks</function> is set to false.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>Windows systems may use different font versions for printing and for screen display, and the spacing of the print version may differ from the spacing of the screen version. This can result in layouts and line breaks differing between the screen display and the printed result. For the best appearance of printed cards in a stack, make sure the stack is closed (and not in memory), then set the stack's <b>formatForPrinting</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to true before opening the <object tag="stack">stack</object> to print it.</p><p/><p><code/><img src="202653"/> <b>Important!</b><code/> Do not edit <keyword tag="field">field</keyword> text in a stack whose <b>formatForPrinting</b> is true. Doing so can cause display <glossary tag="anomaly">anomalies</glossary>. Set the <b>formatForPrinting</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to false before you make changes to text in <glossary tag="field">fields</glossary>.</p><p/><p>The spacing of printer font versions usually results in a difficult-to-read display when these fonts are used for screen viewing. To avoid display problems, set the <b>formatForPrinting</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to true only when printing. To let the user preview the appearance of the printed output, set the <b>formatForPrinting</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to true before opening the <object tag="stack">stack</object>.</p><p/><p><code/><img src="202653"/> <b>Important!</b><code/> <glossary tag="font">Fonts</glossary> <glossary tag="inheritance">inherited</glossary> from another <object tag="stack">stack</object> are not updated when you set the <b>formatForPrinting</b> of a <object tag="stack">stack</object>. If the <object tag="stack">stack</object> will be printed, make sure that either the <glossary tag="stack">stack's</glossary> <property tag="textFont">textFont</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is set to a <glossary tag="font">font</glossary> name (not set to empty), or all <glossary tag="field">fields</glossary> to be printed have their own <glossary tag="font">font</glossary> rather than <glossary tag="inheritance">inheriting</glossary> it.</p><p/><p>If the stack's <b>formatForPrinting</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is true, the setting of the <property tag="windowBoundingRect">windowBoundingRect</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is ignored when the <object tag="stack">stack</object> is opened or <glossary tag="maximize">maximized</glossary>.</p>
  </description>
</doc>