<doc>
  <legacy_id>3497</legacy_id>
  <name>fullscreen</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the fullscreen of <i>stack</i> to { true | false }</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <stack/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <property tag="decorations">decorations Property</property>
    <property tag="iconic">iconic Property</property>
    <function tag="screenRect">screenRect Function</function>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.9">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies whether a stack window takes up the entire screen.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>on mouseUp</p><p>  if the short name of the target is "Full Screen" then</p><p>    set the fullscreen of this stack to the hilite of the target</p><p>  end if</p><p>end mouseUp</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>fullscreen</b> property to change a <object tag="stack">stack's</object> size to make it take up the whole screen.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>fullscreen</b> property of a <object tag="stack">stack</object> is either true or false.</p><p/><p>By default, the <b>fullscreen</b> property of newly created <object tag="stack">stacks</object> is set to false.</p><p/><p>Setting the <b>fullscreen</b> of a <object tag="stack">stack</object> causes the <b>stack</b> to take up all available space on the screen, this includes space occupied by desktop furniture, for example the Taskbar on Windows and the Dock on Mac OS X.</p><p/><p>When the <function tag="screenRect">screenRect</function> is changed, any <object tag="stack">stack</object> with <b>fullscreen</b> set to true will automatically resize to fit the new screen size.</p><p/><p>Changing the size or position of a <object tag="stack">stack</object> with <b>fullscreen</b> set to true will have no effect.</p><p/><p>When a <object tag="stack">stack</object> has its <b>fullscreen</b> set from true to false, the rect of the <object tag="stack">stack</object> is restored to the value it had immediately before the <b>fullscreen</b> was last set to true.</p><p/><p>When a <object tag="stack">stack</object> is full screen, all <property tag="decorations">decorations</property> are removed, however the <property tag="decorations">decorations</property> property still reports the <property tag="decorations">decorations</property> that the <object tag="stack">stack</object> had prior to being made full screen. The <property tag="decorations">decorations</property> are restored when a <object tag="stack">stack</object> is made non-full screen.</p>
  </description>
</doc>