<doc>
	<legacy_id></legacy_id>
	<name>fullscreenmode</name>
	<type>fullscreenmode</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>set the fullscreenmode to {empty|"exact fit"|"show all"|"no border"|"no scale"}</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Sets the full screen scaling mode of a stack.</summary>

	<examples>
<example>set the fullscreenmode to empty</example>
<example>set the fullscreenmode to "no scale"</example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="6.5">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		<changed version=""></changed>
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<server/>
		<web/>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Appearance &amp; Positioning</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>fullscreenmode</b> property to choose the most appropriate full screen scaling mode for the application.</overview>

	<parameters>
		<parameter>
			<name>empty</name>
			<description>The stack is resized (not scaled) to fit the screen. (default) This is the existing behavior.</description>
		</parameter>
		<parameter>
			<name>"exact fit"</name>
			<description>Scale the stack to fill the screen. This stretches the stack if the aspect ratio of the screen does not match that of the stack.</description>
		</parameter>
		<parameter>
			<name>"show all"</name>
			<description>Scale the stack, preserving the aspect ratio, so all content is visible. Some blank space may remain if the screen and stack aspect ratios do not match.</description>
		</parameter>
		<parameter>
			<name>"no border"</name>
			<description>Scale the stack to fill the screen, preserving the aspect ratio. If the stack and screen aspect ratios do not match, the left / right or top / bottom extremes of the stack are not visible.</description>
		</parameter>
		<parameter>
			<name>"no scale"</name>
			<description>The stack is not scaled, but is centered on the screen instead.</description>
		</parameter>

	</parameters>

	<value>The <b>fullscreenmode</b> returns the mode to which this property is set.</value>
	<comments>There are multiple ways in which a stack can be resized or scaled to take full advantage of the available screen space. <b>fullscreenmode</b> allows the developer to choose the most appropriate for their application.<p></p><p><b>Note:</b> The fullscreenmode only takes affect when a stack is full screen. This is the case on mobile platforms where stacks are always full screen, or on the desktop when the <property tag="fullscreen">fullscreen</property> property of the stack is set to true.<p></p><p>The full screen scaling mode is available on all desktop and mobile platforms and operates independently from Hi-DPI support.</p></comments>
	</description>
</doc>
