<doc>
	<legacy_id>1187</legacy_id>
	<name>invisible</name>
	<type>property</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>set the invisible of <i>object</i> to {true | false}</example>
		<example>get the [effective] invisible of <i>object</i></example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
		<synonym>inv</synonym>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Specifies whether an <glossary tag="object">object</glossary> is hidden.</summary>

	<examples>
<example>set the invisible of player "Splash Screen" to false</example>
<example>set the invisible of the mouseControl to true</example>
<example><p>get the effective invisible of button "go"</p></example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		
		<experimental version=""></experimental>
		<nonexperimental version=""></nonexperimental>
	</history>

	<objects>
		<stack/>
		<card/>
		<group/>
		<field/>
		<button/>
		<graphic/>
		<scrollbar/>
		<player/>
		<image/>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<server/>
		<web/>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Appearance &amp; Positioning</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<command tag="show">show Command</command>
		<command tag="hide">hide Command</command>
		<property tag="showInvisibles">showInvisibles Property</property>
		<property tag="visible">visible Property</property>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>invisible</b> property to determine whether an object is hidden or not.</overview>

		<parameters>
		</parameters>

	<value>The <b>invisible</b> of an object is true or false.</value>
	<comments>A hidden object is still present and still takes up memory, and a handler can access its properties and contents, but the user cannot see or or interact with it.<p></p><p>An object that cannot be seen only because it's behind another object is still visible, in the sense that its <b>invisible</b> property is still false.</p><p></p><p>The <b>invisible</b> property of grouped controls is independent of the invisible property of the group. Setting a group's <b>invisible</b> property to true doesn't change the <b>invisible</b> property of its controls; their <b>invisible</b> property is still false, even though the controls cannot be seen because the group is <b>invisible</b>.</p><p></p><p>If you specify the <b>effective</b> keyword the <b>invisible</b> property of a control returns true if the control or any parent group of the control is invisible.</p><p></p><p>You can set the <b>invisible</b> property of a card, but doing so has no effect. Cards cannot be made invisible.</p><p></p><p>The <b>invisible</b> property is the logical inverse of the visible property. When an object's invisible is true, its visible is false, and vice versa.</p></comments>
	</description>
</doc>