<doc>
  <legacy_id>2480</legacy_id>
  <name>liveResizing</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the liveResizing of <i>stack</i> to {true | false}</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <stack/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Windows &amp; Dialog Boxes</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <message tag="resizeStack">resizeStack Message</message>
    <property tag="rectangle">rectangle Property</property>
    <property tag="resizable">resizable Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.1">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Causes a <glossary tag="stack window">stack window</glossary> to display its contents changing during resizing, instead of redrawing the contents after the window is resized.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the liveResizing of stack "Hello World" to false</example>
    <example>set the liveResizing of me to true</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>liveResizing</b> property to create a smooth visual appearance while resizing.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>liveResizing</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> of a <object tag="stack">stack</object> is true or false. By <keyword tag="default">default</keyword>, the <b>liveResizing</b> of a newly created <object tag="stack">stack</object> is set to false.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>When the <b>liveResizing</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is true, the window contents (including the borders) are redrawn continuously as the user resizes, so at any time, the window is displayed as it will look if the user releases the mouse button at that moment.</p><p/><p>If the <b>liveResizing</b> is false, the window does not change until the user releases the mouse and stops resizing.</p><p/><p>If the <b>liveResizing</b> is true, <message tag="resizeStack">resizeStack</message> <glossary tag="message">messages</glossary> are sent continually while the window is being resized, allowing your stack to update its appearance during resizing. (If the user pauses during resizing, with the mouse down in the resize box but the pointer not moving, no <message tag="resizeStack">resizeStack</message> <keyword tag="message box">message</keyword> is sent until the mouse moves again.)</p><p/><p>On Mac OS, Unix, and Windows systems, the <b>liveResizing</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> has no effect.</p>
  </description>
</doc>