<doc>
  <legacy_id>1826</legacy_id>
  <name>pan</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the pan of <i>player</i> to <i>degrees</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <player/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Images &amp; Multimedia</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <property tag="tilt">tilt Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies the current horizontal view angle of a <glossary tag="QuickTime VR">QuickTime VR</glossary> movie.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the pan of player "Arctic" to 90.5</example>
    <example>put the pan of player myPlayerName into myLocation</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>pan</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to find out where the user is in a <glossary tag="QuickTime VR">QuickTime VR</glossary> movie.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>pan</b> is a number between zero and 360.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The user can move the view of a QuickTime VR movie using the navigational controls in the player; a handler can change the view by setting the player's <b>pan</b> and <property tag="tilt">tilt</property> <property tag="properties">properties</property>.</p><p/><p>The <b>pan</b> specifies the amount of rotation in the horizontal plane, in <glossary tag="degree">degrees</glossary>. (Think of a person standing in the middle of a scene and turning from side to side. The point where the person is standing is the <property tag="currentNode">currentNode</property>, and the amount of turning is the <b>pan</b>.) A <b>pan</b> of zero corresponds to the straight-ahead view of the scene. As the viewer turns clockwise, the <b>pan</b> increases.</p><p/><p>If you set the <b>pan</b> of a player to a <i>number</i> outside the range zero to 360, no <glossary tag="error">error</glossary> results, but the <b>pan</b> is set to<code><i>number</i> mod 360</code>. For example, if you attempt to set the <b>pan</b> of a <keyword tag="player">player</keyword> to -20, its <b>pan</b> is actually set to 340.</p><p/><p>The <b>pan</b> is limited by the <glossary tag="player">player's</glossary> <property tag="constraints">constraints</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary>. If you specify a <b>pan</b> greater than the <glossary tag="range">range</glossary> permitted by the <property tag="constraints">constraints</property>, the <b>pan</b> is set to the highest permitted <function tag="value">value</function>. If you specify a <b>pan</b> less than the <glossary tag="range">range</glossary> permitted by the <property tag="constraints">constraints</property>, the <b>pan</b> is set to the lowest permitted <function tag="value">value</function>.</p><p/><p>If the player does not contain a QuickTime VR movie, its <b>pan</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is zero.</p>
  </description>
</doc>