<doc>	<legacy_id>3004</legacy_id>	<name>qtIdleRate</name>	<type>property</type>	<syntax>		<example>set the qtIdleRate to <i>number</i></example>		<example>get the qtIdleRate</example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>The global property <b>qtIdleRate</b> specifies how frequently to idle QuickTime movies.</summary>	<examples><example>set the qtIdleRate to 50</example><example>put the qtIdleRate into tQtIdleRate</example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="2.7">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>			</history>	<objects>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<server/>		<web/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>	</classification>	<references>		<function tag="QTVersion">QTVersion Function</function>	</references>	<description>Use the <b>qtIdleRate</b> in conjunction with the global <property tag="idleRate">idleRate property</property> to control updating of QT movies. Increasing the <b>qtIdleRate</b> causes less frequent updates, and decreases the amount of CPU time the application uses.<p></p><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>qtIdleRate</b> is an integer between 1 and 65535.</p><p></p><p>By default, the <b>qtIdleRate</b> property is set to 50 (one-twentieth of a second).</p><p></p><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The <b>qtIdleRate</b> is the time in milliseconds between one update of a player and the next.</p><p></p><p>Updating gives the player object time to redraw the video or other media being played. A higher idle rate will result in smoother playback but will also require more cpu time. </p><p></p><p>LiveCode uses the following heuristics to determine how frequently to idle QT players:</p><p></p><p>If the version of QT &lt; 6 then it idles at the <b>qtIdleRate</b> at all times.</p><p></p><p>If the version of QT &gt;=6 then:</p><p>        * If no players are playing and none of the visible players have interactive movies assigned they are idled at the <b>qtIdleRate.</b></p><p>        * If no players are playing, but one of more of the visible players are interactive then they are idled at the <b>qtIdleRate.</b></p><p>        * If players are playing then they are idled at the <b>qtIdleRate</b>.</p><p>  </p><p>Interactive movies are ones such as QTVR and Flash that need to periodically check for input and update themselves.</p><p></p><p></p><note>The <b>qtIdleRate</b> property has no effect on Windows if the <property tag="dontUseQT">dontUseQT property</property> is true.</note></description></doc>