<doc>
  <legacy_id>1989</legacy_id>
  <name>revProfile</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the revProfile of <i>object</i> to <i>profileName</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library>Profile library</library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
    <synonym>cRevGeneral[&quot;profile&quot;]</synonym>
    <synonym>profile</synonym>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Values  Properties</category>
    <category>Standalone Applications</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="revSetStackFileProfile">revSetStackFileProfile Command</command>
    <property tag="customPropertySets">customPropertySets Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies the current <property tag="revProfile">profile</property> for an <glossary tag="object">object</glossary>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the revProfile of button "OK" to "French"</example>
    <example>set the revProfile of group "Menubar" to "Short Menus"</example>
    <example>set the revProfile of me to "Master"</example>
    <example>if the revProfile of this stack is "LargeFont" then beep</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>revProfile</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to switch sets of property values on the fly.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>revProfile</b> of an object is the name of one of the object's <glossary tag="property profile">profiles</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>When you change the value of a property for an object, the value is stored in the object's current profile. If you later switch back to that profile, the stored values are restored. For example, if you create a profile named "Fluffy" for a button, then set the button's <b>backgroundColor</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to "pink", that setting of the <property tag="backgroundColor">backgroundColor</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is stored with the Fluffy <property tag="revProfile">profile</property>. If you later set the <glossary tag="button">button's</glossary> <property tag="revProfile">profile</property> to "Fluffy", the pink color is restored.</p><p/><p>If the <i>profileName</i> does not exist for the <i>object</i>, setting the <property tag="revProfile">profile</property> either causes an error or creates a new <property tag="revProfile">profile</property> with that name for the <glossary tag="object">object</glossary>. You change this setting in the "Property Profiles" pane of the Preferences window.</p><p/><p>(The <b>revProfile</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is implemented as a <property tag="customProperties">custom property</property>, part of the "cRevGeneral" <property tag="customProperties">custom property</property> set. For this reason, you can also refer to it using the <property tag="customProperties">custom property</property> set notation, as cRevGeneral["profile"].)</p><p/><p><img src="202653"/> <b>Important!</b> The <b>revProfile</b> property is part of the Profile library. To ensure that the property works in a standalone application, in the Profiles section on the General screen of the Standalone Application Settings window, make sure you choose to include profiles in your application.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> When included in a standalone application, the Profile library is implemented as a hidden group and made available when the group receives its first openBackground message. During the first part of the applicati startup process, before this message is sent, the <b>revProfile</b> property is not yet available. This may affect attempts to use this property in startup, preOpenStack, openStack, or preOpenCard hand in the main stack. Once the application has finished starting up, the library is available and the <b>revProfile</b> property can be used in any handler.</p>
  </description>
</doc>