<doc>
	<legacy_id></legacy_id>
	<name>sessionLifetime</name>
	<type>property</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>set the sessionLifetime to <i>duration</i></example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Specifies the maximum duration in seconds for which session data is retained between uses.</summary>

	<examples>
<example>set the sessionLifetime to tSessionDuration</example>
<example>set the sessionLifetime to 3600 --<i> sets the duration of the session to an hour</i></example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="5.0">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		
	</history>

	<objects>
		<global/>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<server/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<property tag="sessionName">sessionName Property</property>
		<property tag="sessionID">sessionID Property</property>
		<property tag="sessionSavePath">sessionSavePath Property</property>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>sessionLifetime</b> property to set the the maximum duration for which session data is retained between uses.</overview>

		<parameters>
  <parameter>
    <name>duration</name>
    <description>the duration of a session, in seconds</description>
  </parameter>		</parameters>

	<value></value>
	<comments>Use the <b>sessionLifetime</b> property to set the the duration, in seconds, for which session data is retained. The <b>sessionLifetime</b> specifies how long a session will remain active, accessing the session data resets the countdown to expiry to the <b>sessionLifetime</b>.<p></p><p>For example if the <b>sessionLifetime</b> is 360 seconds (10 minutes) and 10 minutes pass without the session being used the session will expire. A session can last indefinitely as long as the session data is accessed at regular intervals no further apart than the <b>sessionLifetime</b>.</p><p></p><p>If the <b>sessionLifetime</b> is not specifed the default of 24 minutes is used.</p><p></p><p></p><note>You do not need to alter any of the session properties in order to start and use sessions. They provide a way for advanced users to configure the way session work.</note><p></p><p></p><note>The <b>sessionCookieName </b>property is only available when running in CGI mode (Server).</note></comments>
	</description>
</doc>