<doc>
	<legacy_id>1789</legacy_id>
	<name>shadow</name>
	<type>property</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>set the shadow of <i>object</i> to {true | false}</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Specifies whether a <keyword tag="button">button</keyword>, <keyword tag="field">field</keyword>, or stack window is drawn with a drop shadow.   </summary>

	<examples>
<example>set the shadow of field ID 18 to true</example>
<example>set the shadow of this stack to false</example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="1.0">Added.   </introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		<changed version="2.1">2.1</changed>
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
	  <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<server/>
		<web/>
	  <mobile/>
  </classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Appearance &amp; Positioning</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>shadow</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to draw a drop shadow.   </overview>

		<parameters>
		</parameters>

	<value>The <b>shadow</b> of an <glossary tag="object">object</glossary> is true or false.   <p></p><p>By default, the <b>shadow</b> of a newly created <object tag="stack">stack</object> is set to true. The <b>shadow</b> of a newly created <keyword tag="control">control</keyword> is false by <keyword tag="default">default</keyword>, but may be true if it is created by the <glossary tag="development environment">development environment</glossary>. (For example, choosing Object menu &gt; New Control &gt; Shadow Button creates a button whose <b>shadow</b> is true.)</p></value>
	<comments>While the <b>shadow</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> can be set for any <keyword tag="control">control</keyword>, it affects the appearance of only <glossary tag="field">fields</glossary> and <glossary tag="button">buttons</glossary>. Other <glossary tag="control">controls</glossary> do not display a drop shadow, regardless of the setting of their <b>shadow</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary>. <p></p><p>The <b>shadow</b> of a <glossary tag="stack window">stack window</glossary> is drawn by the operating system. On <glossary tag="Mac OS">Mac OS</glossary>, <glossary tag="Unix">Unix</glossary>, and <glossary tag="Windows">Windows systems</glossary>, the setting of a <glossary tag="stack">stack's</glossary> <b>shadow</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> has no effect. </p><p></p><p>The setting of this property for a stack affects the stack's <b>decorations</b> property, and vice versa. Setting a stack's <b>shadow</b> property determines whether its <b>decorations</b> property includes &quot;noShadow&quot; (or is &quot;default&quot;, for window styles that normally include a drop shadow). Conversely, setting a stack's <b>decorations</b> property sets its <b>shadow</b> to true or false depending on whether the <b>decorations</b> includes &quot;noShadow&quot; (or is &quot;default&quot;). </p><p></p><p>By default, the shadow extends 4 <property tag="pixels">pixels</property> to the left and below the <glossary tag="object">object</glossary>. You can change the size and direction of the drop shadow with the <property tag="shadowOffset">shadowOffset</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary>. (The <property tag="shadowOffset">shadowOffset</property> has no effect on <glossary tag="stack window">stack windows</glossary>.)</p><p></p><p></p><change><p>The ability to specify the <b>shadow</b> of a <object tag="stack">stack</object> was added in version 2. 1. </change></comments>
	</description>
</doc>