<doc>	<legacy_id></legacy_id>	<name>sharedBehavior</name>	<type>property</type>	<syntax>		<example>set the sharedBehavior of group myGroup to {true | false}</example>		<example>get the sharedBehavior of group myGroup</example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Specifies whether the group will behave as a shared group.</summary>	<examples><example>set the sharedBehavior of group 1 to true</example><example><p>get the sharedBehavior of group &quot;myGroupName&quot;</p><p>put it into tSharedBehavior</p></example><example><p>put the sharedBehavior of group myGroup into tSharedBehavior</p></example><example><p>set the sharedBehavior of group 1 to true</p><p>place group 1 on card 2 of this stack</p></example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="4.6.4">Added</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>			</history>	<objects>		<group/>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>		<ios/>		<android/>		<windows_mobile/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<server/>		<web/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>	</classification>	<references>		<command tag="place">place Command</command>		<command tag="remove">remove Command</command>		<command tag="delete">delete Command</command>		<property tag="sharedGroupIds">sharedGroupIds Property</property>		<property tag="sharedGroupNames">sharedGroupNames Property</property>		<property tag="backgroundBehavior">backgroundBehavior Property</property>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use the <b>sharedBehavior</b> property to make a group behave as a shared group and <command tag="place">place</command> it on more than one card.</overview>		<parameters>		</parameters>	<value>The <b>sharedBehavior</b> of a group is true or false.<p></p><p>By default, the <b>sharedBehavior</b> property of newly created groups is set to false.</p></value>	<comments>Only top-level groups may be shared groups; an attempt to set the <b>sharedBehavior</b> of a nested group to true will throw an error.<p></p><p>A shared group behaves identically to a normal group except that it is not owned by any one card. This means that if a shared group is present on only one card and that card is deleted, the shared group will not be deleted. Instead, the group will become 'unplaced', allowing it to placed onto other cards in the future.</p><p></p><p></p><note>The group can still be explicitly deleted using the <command tag="delete">delete</command> command, in which case it will be removed from all cards on which it is placed. </note><p></p><p>An attempt to set the <b>sharedBehavior</b> of a shared group to false when it is placed on more than one card, or not placed on any cards will through an error. To change a shared group to a normal group, the group must be present on exactly one card.</p></comments>	</description></doc>