<doc>
  <legacy_id>3502</legacy_id>
  <name>stackFileVersion</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the stackFileVersion to <i>version</i></example>
    <example>the stackFileVersion</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <global/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <object tag="stack">stack Object</object>
    <command tag="save">save Command</command>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.7">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="5.5.0">Added version 5.5</changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Reports the version of the stack file format to use.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>command legacySave pStack</p><p>  local tOldStackFileVersion</p><p>  put the stackFileVersion into tOldStackFileVersion</p><p>  set the stackFileVersion to 2.4</p><p>  save stack pStack</p><p>  set the stackFileVersion to tOldStackFileVersion</p><p>end legacySave</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>stackFileVersion</b> to obtain or change which version of the stack file format LiveCode will use when saving stacks.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>stackFileVersion</b> currently has two possible values:</p><p>  - "2.4" - This stack file version is used by LiveCode 2.6.1 and earlier</p><p>  - "2.7" - This stack file version is used by versions of LiveCode after 2.6.1 and before 5.5.0.</p><p>  - "5.5" - This stack file version is used by versions of LiveCode 5.5.0 and after.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The <b>stackFileVersion</b> is useful when stacks need to be saved in legacy formats for backwards compatibility but it should be used with caution.</p><p/><p>Setting the <b>stackFileVersion</b> to something less than the current version could result in data being lost when stacks are saved, in particular any features that are not present in the target version. For example setting the <b>stackFileVersion</b> to 2.4 will cause any <property tag="blendLevel">blendLevel</property> or <property tag="ink">ink</property> properties to be lost.</p><p/><p>Remember to set the <b>stackFileVersion</b> back to its previous value after changing it, otherwise LiveCode may save your stacks in unexpected formats.</p><p/><p>There is no need to use the <b>stackFileVersion</b> to save a stack compatible with version 2.6.1 and earlier in the IDE. Instead, open the stack in the current version of LiveCode and select "Save As" from the "File" menu, then choose "Legacy LiveCode Stack" from the drop down box for the file type. If you do not wish to do this every time, there is a setting in the "Files &amp; Memory" section of the preferences that causes LiveCode to preserve the stack file version of legacy stacks.</p><p/><p>The following properties are not supported in the 2.4 stack file format and will be lost or altered when saving in 2.4 format:</p><p/><p><property tag="antialiased">antialiased property</property> - lost</p><p><property tag="ink">ink property</property> - lost for cards, reverted to GXcopy for controls if not supported</p><p><property tag="opaque">opaque property</property> - lost for cards</p><p><property tag="blendLevel">blendLevel property</property> - lost</p><p/><p>The following properties are not supported in the 2.7 stack file format and will be lost or altered when saving in 2.7 format:</p><p/><p><property tag="textFont">textFont property</property> - separation lost</p><p><property tag="textStyle">textStyle property</property> - separation lost</p><p><property tag="textSize">textSize property</property> - separation lost</p><p><property tag="textFont">textFont property</property> - separation lost</p><p><property tag="unicodeToolTip">unicodeToolTip property</property> - lost</p><p>all paragraph level properties - lost</p> 
    <p>separation of Unicode attribute of chars - lost</p><p>character level metadata property - lost</p> 
        
  </description>
</doc>