<doc>
  <legacy_id>1822</legacy_id>
  <name>umask</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the umask to <i>permissionsString</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <global/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>The System Environment</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="create folder">create folder Command</command>
    <function tag="files">files Function</function>
    <function tag="folders">folders Function</function>
    <command tag="open file">open file Command</command>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
    <disk access="???"/>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies the <glossary tag="Unix">Unix</glossary> access permissions of <function tag="files">files</function> and <function tag="folders">folders</function> created by the <glossary tag="application">application</glossary>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the umask to 002 <code><i>-- owner read/write, anyone can read</i></code></example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>umask</b> command to set the access permissions for <function tag="files">files</function> and <function tag="folders">folders</function> you create.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>umask</b> is a positive <keyword tag="integer">integer</keyword> of three digits, or empty.</p><p/><p>By default, the <b>umask</b> is set to the user's <glossary tag="Unix">Unix</glossary> "umask" setting.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The <b>umask</b> blocks the specified permissions from being granted for newly created <function tag="files">files</function> and <function tag="folders">folders</function>. It affects <function tag="files">files</function> created with the <command tag="open file">open file</command> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary>, <function tag="folders">folders</function> created with the <command tag="create folder">create folder</command> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary>, and <function tag="files">files</function> and <function tag="folders">folders</function> created on the local system with the <keyword tag="URL">URL</keyword> <glossary tag="keyword">keyword</glossary>.</p><p/><p>Each digit of the <b>umask</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is an <glossary tag="octal">octal</glossary> number that specifies a set of permissions:</p><p/><p>        * Read permission (4) lets a user read or copy the file or folder.</p><p>        * Write permission (2) lets a user change the contents of the file or folder.</p><p>        * Execute permission (1) lets a user run the file (if it is a program file), or work with files in the folder.</p><p/><p>You add the numbers corresponding to each permission together to get the digit. For example, to specify that write permission is to be blocked, use the digit<code> 2</code>. To specify that read and execute permission should both be blocked, use the digit<code> 5 </code>(4 + 1).</p><p/><p>The first digit of the <b>umask</b> specifies the permissions to be blocked for the owner of the <keyword tag="file">file</keyword> or <property tag="defaultFolder">folder</property>; the second digit specifies the permissions to be blocked for members of the group that owns the <keyword tag="file">file</keyword>; and the third digit specifies permissions to be blocked for all other users. For example, if the <b>umask</b> is<code> 022</code> when LiveCode creates a file, the file owner has all the normal permissions, but the group and all other users do not have write permission, even if LiveCode would normally create the file so as to give them write permission.</p><p/><p>On Mac OS and Windows systems, the <b>umask</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> has no effect and always reports zero.</p>
  </description>
</doc>