<doc>
	<legacy_id>3078</legacy_id>
	<name>unicodeTitle</name>
	<type>property</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>set the unicodeTitle of stack to titleString</example>
		<example></example>
		<example></example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Specifies the string shown in a stack window's title bar as a unicode string.</summary>

	<examples>
<example><p>set the unicodeTitle of stack "My Stack" to uniEncode("My Stack's Name")</p></example>
<example><p>set the unicodeTitle of stack "My Stack" to tUTF16EncodedString</p></example>
<example><p></p></example>
<example><p></p></example>
<example><p></p></example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="2.9">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version="7.0">7.0</deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		
		<experimental version=""></experimental>
		<nonexperimental version=""></nonexperimental>
	</history>

	<objects>
		<stack/>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<server/>
		<web/>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<function tag="uniEncode">uniEncode function</function>
		<property tag="label">label property</property>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>unicodeTitle</b> property to set the title of a stack's window to a unicode string, or to get the current title of a stack's window as a unicode string.</overview>

		<parameters>
		</parameters>

	<value>The <b>unicodeTitle</b> of an object is a string of double-byte characters in the same format as returned from functions such as uniEncode.</value>
	<comments><p>Windows 98SE and Windows ME do not support unicode window titles. On these systems, the string displayed in the title bar will be the closest approximation possible on the running system.</p><p></p><p>Deprecated: In LiveCode 7.0 the language was changed to handle unicode transparently. This means that language functionality which previously aided unicode text manipulation is no longer required. This property should not be used in new code; simply set the title as normal. Assigning values other than those returned from uniEncode to this property will not produce the desired results.The following are now equivalent:</p><p></p><p>set the unicodeTitle of this stack to tText</p><p>set the title of this stack to textDecode(tText, "UTF16")</p></comments>
	</description>
</doc>