<doc>
  <legacy_id>1659</legacy_id>
  <name>windowBoundingRect</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the windowBoundingRect to <i>left</i>,<i>top</i>,<i>right</i>,<i>bottom</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <global/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Windows &amp; Dialog Boxes</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <property tag="maxWidth">maxWidth Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies the rectangle in which windows may open and <property tag="zoom">zoom</property> or <keyword tag="maximize">maximize</keyword>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the windowBoundingRect to 100,20,800,600</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>windowBoundingRect</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to ensure free space on the screen for toolbars or other information on the screen.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>windowBoundingRect</b> consists of four <glossary tag="integer">integers</glossary> separated by commas.  By default the coordinates are in the same format as those returned by the <function tag="screenRect">screenRect</function>. This means they are relative to the topleft of the primary monitor and may therefore be negative.  </p><p/><p>On <glossary tag="Mac OS">Mac OS systems</glossary>, the <keyword tag="default">default</keyword> <b>windowBoundingRect</b> is adjusted to leave room for the <glossary tag="menu bar">menu bar</glossary>. On <glossary tag="Windows">Windows systems</glossary>, the <keyword tag="default">default</keyword> <b>windowBoundingRect</b> is adjusted to leave room for the <glossary tag="task bar">task bar</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>When the user zooms (on Mac OS systems) or maximizes (on Unix and Windows systems) the window, its zoomed or maximized size is constrained by the <b>windowBoundingRect</b>.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> Users can drag or resize windows to extend outside the <b>windowBoundingRect</b>, and a <glossary tag="handler">handler</glossary> can move or resize a window so that it's outside the <b>windowBoundingRect</b>. This <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> constrains the <keyword tag="default">default</keyword> position of windows when they open or <property tag="zoom">zoom</property>, but does not prevent them from being manually resized or repositioned.</p><p/><p>The <b>windowBoundingRect</b> <function tag="value">value</function> is checked against the window's position before the <message tag="preOpenStack">preOpenStack</message> <keyword tag="message box">message</keyword> is sent. This means that if you want a <object tag="stack">stack</object> to extend outside the <b>windowBoundingRect</b>, you should set its <keyword tag="rectangle">rectangle</keyword> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to the desired value in a <message tag="preOpenStack">preOpenStack</message> <glossary tag="handler">handler</glossary>. This ensures that the window is enlarged to the size you specify before it appears, instead of being resized when the <b>windowBoundingRect</b> is checked.</p><p/><p>The value of the <b>windowBoundingRect</b> does not affect <command tag="palette">palette</command>, <command tag="modal">modal</command>, or <command tag="modeless">modeless</command> windows. Only stacks whose <property tag="mode">mode</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is 1 or 2 are affected.</p><p/><p>If a stack's <b>formatForPrinting</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is set to true, the <b>windowBoundingRect</b> is ignored when the <object tag="stack">stack</object> is opened.</p><p/><p>The value of the <b>windowBoundingRect</b> is not updated automatically when you change the screen resolution or when you move items such as the Windows task bar. For example, if the <b>windowBoundingRect</b> is set to 0,0,640,480, it is not changed if you change the screen resolution to 1024x768. If you change the screen settings after starting up the application, make sure the value of the <b>windowBoundingRect</b> property is still appropriate.</p><p/><p>Changing the <b>windowBoundingRect</b> does not affect the position of windows that are already open.</p>
  </description>
</doc>