<doc>
  <legacy_id>1560</legacy_id>
  <name>zoom</name>
  <type>property</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>set the zoom of <i>player</i> to <i>degrees</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
    <player/>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Images &amp; Multimedia</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <property tag="tilt">tilt Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Specifies the field of view of a <glossary tag="QuickTime VR">QuickTime VR</glossary> movie.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>set the zoom of player "Arctic" to 45 <code><i>-- medium field of view</i></code></example>
    <example>put the zoom of player myPlayerName into currentField</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>zoom</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to find out how much of a <glossary tag="QuickTime VR">QuickTime VR</glossary> movie the user can see at one time.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>zoom</b> of a <keyword tag="player">player</keyword> is a number between zero and 90.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The user can change the field of view of a QuickTime VR movie using the navigational controls in the player; a handler can change the view by setting the player's <b>zoom</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary>.</p><p/><p>The <b>zoom</b> specifies the angle of the viewer's field of view, in <glossary tag="degree">degrees</glossary>. (Think of a camera with a zoom lens.) As the <b>zoom</b> increases, more of the scene can be seen. As the <b>zoom</b> decreases, the edges of the scene are no longer visible, but the center of the scene is shown in greater detail. A <b>zoom</b> of zero corresponds to the closest detailed view of a single point; a <b>zoom</b> of 90 corresponds to a wide-angle view of the scene.</p><p/><p>The <b>zoom</b> is limited by the <glossary tag="player">player's</glossary> <property tag="constraints">constraints</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary>. If you specify a <b>zoom</b> greater than the <glossary tag="range">range</glossary> permitted by the <property tag="constraints">constraints</property>, the <b>zoom</b> is set to the highest permitted <function tag="value">value</function>. If you specify a <b>zoom</b> less than the <glossary tag="range">range</glossary> permitted by the <property tag="constraints">constraints</property>, the <b>zoom</b> is set to the lowest permitted <function tag="value">value</function>.</p><p/><p>If the player does not contain a QuickTime VR movie, its <b>zoom</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is zero.</p>
  </description>
</doc>