<doc>
	<legacy_id>2420</legacy_id>
	<name>is not a</name>
	<type>operator</type>

	<syntax>
		<example><i>value</i> is not a[n] {boolean | integer | number | point | rect| date | color | ASCII string}</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
		<synonym>is not an</synonym>
	</synonyms>

	<summary><glossary tag="evaluate">Evaluates</glossary> to true if a <function tag="value">value</function> is not of the specified type, false otherwise. </summary>

	<examples>
<example>22 is not a number </example>
<example>CJ22 is not a number </example>
<example>numToChar(128) is not an ASCII string <i>-- evaluates to true</i></example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="1.0">Added. </introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
	  <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<server/>
		<web/>
	  <mobile/>
  </classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Math, Logic, &amp; Dates</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<keyword tag="point">point Keyword</keyword>
		<keyword tag="integer">integer Keyword</keyword>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>is not a</b> <glossary tag="operator">operator</glossary> to <glossary tag="validate">validate</glossary> data to make sure it's not the wrong type. </overview>

	<parameters>
    <parameter>The <i>value</i> is any source of value.</parameter>
  </parameters>

	<value></value>
	<comments>This operator is useful for checking whether the user has entered data correctly, and for checking parameters before sending them to a handler to avoid a script error caused by feeding data of one type to an operator or function that requires a different type. <p></p><p>A <i>value</i> is a:</p><p></p><p>&#9;* boolean or logical if it is one of the two constants <b>true</b> or false</p><p></p><p>&#9;* integer if it consists of digits (with an optional minus sign)</p><p></p><p>&#9;* number if it consists of digits, optional leading minus sign, optional decimal point, and optional &quot;E&quot; or &quot;e&quot; (scientific notation)</p><p></p><p>&#9;* point if it consists of two numbers separated by a comma</p><p></p><p>&#9;* rect if it consists of four numbers separated by commas</p><p></p><p>&#9;* date if it is in one of the formats produced by the <b>date</b> or <function tag="time">time</function> functions</p><p></p><p>&#9;* color if it is a valid color reference</p><p></p><p>&#9;* ASCII string if it does not contain any characters greater than charToNum(127)</p><p></p><p>All the types other than boolean can also include leading or trailing white space characters. </p><p></p><p>The <b>is not a</b> <glossary tag="operator">operator</glossary> is the logical inverse of the <operator tag="is a">is a</operator> <glossary tag="operator">operator</glossary>. When one is true, the other is false. </p></comments>
	</description>
</doc>