<doc>
  <legacy_id>1353</legacy_id>
  <name>/**/</name>
  <type>keyword</type>
  <syntax>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
    <synonym>/*</synonym>
    <synonym>*/</synonym>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Writing LiveCode</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <keyword tag="--">-- Keyword</keyword>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary><glossary tag="delimit">Delimits</glossary> a <glossary tag="block comment">block comment</glossary>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>answer whichPrompt /* use the prompt that was set earlier */</example>
    <example>/* This entire block, although it is two lines</p><p>   long, is a single comment. */</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Anything between <b>/*</b> and <b>*/</b> is treated as a <glossary tag="comment">comment</glossary> and is ignored by LiveCode when <glossary tag="execute">executing</glossary> the <glossary tag="handler">handler</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>Comments are useful for documenting and explaining your code, either for others who might need to read and modify it, or for yourself. (The code may be clear in your mind now, but in six months, you'll be glad you included comments.)</p><p/><p>The block comments created by <b>/**/</b> differ from the line <glossary tag="comment">comments</glossary> created by <i>--</i> because a <glossary tag="block comment">block comment</glossary> can span multiple <keyword tag="lines">lines</keyword>, as well as a single <keyword tag="line">line</keyword> or part of a <keyword tag="line">line</keyword>. (A <glossary tag="comment">comment</glossary> marked by <keyword tag="--">--</keyword> extends only to the end of the <keyword tag="line">line</keyword>.) A <glossary tag="comment">comment</glossary> that starts with<code> /* </code>does not end until<code> */</code>, even if there are several lines in between.</p><p/><p>Comments can be placed anywhere in a script--inside handlers or outside all handlers. In a long script with many handlers, it may be useful to divide the handlers into sections. Each section starts with a comment containing the section name and any other useful information. This practice helps you keep long scripts organized. Similarly, a lengthy handler can be made more readable by explanatory comments.</p><p/><p>Comments can contain any text, including lines of LiveCode. If the code is within a comment, it's ignored. You can temporarily remove sections of code for debugging by putting those sections inside a comment.</p>
  </description>
</doc>