<doc>
  <legacy_id>1083</legacy_id>
  <name>answer file</name>
  <type>command</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>answer file[s] <i>prompt</i> [with <i>defaultPath</i>] [{with filter | of type} <i>types</i>] [titled <i>windowTitle</i>] [as sheet]</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Windows &amp; Dialog Boxes</category>
    <category>Files, Folders, &amp; Resources</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="answer">answer Command</command>
    <command tag="answer file with type">answer file with type Command</command>
    <command tag="answer folder">answer folder Command</command>
    <command tag="ask file">ask file Command</command>
    <command tag="ask file with type">ask file with type Command</command>
    <function tag="files">files Function</function>
    <keyword tag="it">it Keyword</keyword>
    <function tag="revMacFromUnixPath">revMacFromUnixPath Function</function>
    <function tag="revUnixFromMacPath">revUnixFromMacPath Function</function>
    <property tag="systemFileSelector">systemFileSelector Property</property>
    <command tag="revCopyFile">revCopyFile Command</command>
    <command tag="open file">open file Command</command>
    <property tag="dontUseNS">dontUseNS Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="2.6"></changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
    <disk access="???"/>
  </security>
  <summary>Displays a <glossary tag="file dialog box">standard file dialog</glossary> for the user to select a <keyword tag="file">file</keyword>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>answer file "Select a file to delete:"</example>
    <example>answer files "Select the files you wish to process:"</example>
    <example>answer file "Input:" with "/Macintosh HD/"</example>
    <example>answer file (field "Prompt") of type "RSTK"</example>
    <example>answer file empty with filter "JPEGs,*.jpg" </example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>answer file</b> command when a <glossary tag="handler">handler</glossary> needs the <glossary tag="file path">file path</glossary> of a <keyword tag="file">file</keyword> before continuing.</p><p/><p><b>Parameters:</b></p><p>The <i>prompt</i> is a <keyword tag="string">string</keyword> (or any <glossary tag="expression">expression</glossary> that <glossary tag="evaluate">evaluates</glossary> to a <keyword tag="string">string</keyword>). If you specify empty, no <glossary tag="prompt">prompt</glossary> appears.</p><p>The <i>defaultPath</i> is the <glossary tag="file path">name and location</glossary> of the <property tag="defaultFolder">folder</property> whose contents are listed when the <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog box</glossary> appears. If no <i>defaultPath</i> is specified, the <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog box</glossary> lists the contents of the last folder you used with a <glossary tag="file dialog box">file dialog box</glossary>.</p><p/><p>The <i>windowTitle</i>, if specified, appears in the <glossary tag="title bar">title bar</glossary> of the <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog box</glossary>. If no <i>windowTitle</i> is given, the <glossary tag="title bar">title bar</glossary> is blank. (This <glossary tag="parameter">parameter</glossary> has no effect on <glossary tag="Mac OS">Mac OS systems</glossary>, because <glossary tag="Mac OS">Mac OS</glossary> <glossary tag="file dialog box">file dialog</glossary> boxes don't have a <glossary tag="title bar">title bar</glossary>.)</p><p>Use the <i>types</i> <glossary tag="parameter">parameter</glossary> to specify which <function tag="files">files</function> should appear and be available for selection.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The dialog box displayed is the same one most programs use for the "Open" command in the File menu.</p><p>The absolute file path of the file the user chose is placed in the <b>it</b> <glossary tag="variable">variable</glossary>. If the answer files form is used, a return-delimited list of such paths is placed in the <b>it</b> variable. If the user cancels the <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog</glossary>, the <keyword tag="it">it</keyword> <glossary tag="variable">variable</glossary> is set to empty, and the <function tag="result">result</function> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st> <glossary tag="return">returns</glossary> "Cancel".</p><p/><p><img src="202653"/> <b>Important!</b> The <command tag="answer file">answer file command</command> does not open the <keyword tag="file">file</keyword>. It only displays the dialog box and retrieves the path to the file the user specifies.</p><p/><p>If the as sheet form is used, the dialog box appears as a sheet on OS X systems. On other systems, the as sheet form has no effect and the dialog box appears normally. Attempting to open a sheet from within another sheet displays the second <i>stack</i> as a <glossary tag="modal dialog box">modal dialog box</glossary> instead.  To give a dialog box a prompt when using the as sheet form a non-empty title must be provided.  This will cause the prompt to appear in the same place it would if as sheet was not being used.</p><p/><p>If the <b>systemFileSelector</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is set to false, LiveCode's built-in <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog box</glossary> is used instead of the operating system's <glossary tag="file dialog box">standard file dialog</glossary>.</p><p/><p>The way file types are specified depends on the platform:</p><p><b>Filtering for Mac OS:</b>  You can use either with filter or of type. With either form, the <i>types</i> <glossary tag="parameter">parameter</glossary> consists of one or more 4-<keyword tag="character">characterfile types</keyword>, <glossary tag="concatenate">concatenated</glossary>. For example, to display <keyword tag="text">text</keyword> and <glossary tag="PICT">PICT</glossary>-<function tag="format">formatfiles</function> but no others, use a <i>types</i> <glossary tag="parameter">parameter</glossary> of "TEXTPICT". To display applications only, use a <i>types</i> <glossary tag="parameter">parameter</glossary> of "APPL".</p><p/><p>If the <i>types</i> <keyword tag="string">string</keyword> is shorter than four <keyword tag="characters">characters</keyword> (on a <glossary tag="Mac OS">Mac OS system</glossary>), the <function tag="files">files</function> are not filtered: all <function tag="files">files</function> appear in the <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog box</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Filtering for OS X:</b>  Works the same as filtering for <glossary tag="Mac OS">Mac OS</glossary>, except that if one of the <glossary tag="type signature">file types</glossary> is "APPL", the dialog box displays <glossary tag="application bundle">application bundles</glossary> as well as single-file applications.</p><p/><p><b>Filtering for Unix:</b> You must use the with filter form if you want to specify one or more types: the of type form can't be used on Unix systems. The <i>types</i> <glossary tag="parameter">parameter</glossary> consists of a single <glossary tag="wildcard">wildcard expression</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Filtering for Windows:</b> You must use the with filter form to specify one or more types: the of type form can't be used on Windows systems. A <glossary tag="type signature">file type</glossary> consists of an optional description, a line feed or comma, and one or more <glossary tag="extension">file extension</glossary> specifications:</p><p><i>  [description</i>], *.<i>extension</i> [; *.<i>extension</i>...]</p><p/><p>For example, to specify that only LiveCode files should appear in the dialog box, use this statement. The description "LiveCode files" is visible to the user at the bottom of the dialog, and only files with the extension ".rev" are shown:</p><p>  answer file myPrompt with filter "LiveCode files,*.rev"</p><p/><p>You can specify more than one file extension for a single description. For example, to specify that only JPEG, GIF, and PNG files should appear, use this statement:</p><p>  answer file myPrompt with filter "Web Graphics,*.jpg;*.gif;*.png"</p><p/><p>You can include several descriptions, along with their file types, by separating them with commas. The descriptions appear in the list at the bottom of the file dialog box. For example, if you want to display all text and Microsoft Word files, use this command:</p><p>  answer file myPrompt with filter "Text files,*.txt,MS Word files,*.doc"</p><p/><p><img src="202651"/> <b>Tip:</b> If a set of filters is complex or if you use them in several places, it may be easier to put them into a <glossary tag="variable">variable</glossary>, then use that <glossary tag="variable">variable</glossary> in the <b>answer file</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Changes:</b></p><p>The ability to use answer file...of type "APPL" to designate an OS X application bundle was introduced in version 2.0. In previous versions, the APPL file type showed only atomic files of type "APPL".</p><p>The answer file...as sheet form was introduced in version 2.0.</p><p>The answer files ... form was introduced in version 2.6.</p>
  </description>
</doc>