<doc>
	<legacy_id>2066</legacy_id>
	<name>ask password</name>
	<type>command</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>ask password [clear] <i>question</i> [with <i>defaultAnswer</i>] [titled <i>windowTitle</i>] [as sheet]</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Displays a <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog box</glossary> like the <command tag="ask">ask</command> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary>, but with the characters the user types displayed as asterisks (*) for privacy.</summary>

	<examples>
<example>ask password &quot;Please enter password&quot;</p><p>get mcEncrypt(it)</p><p></example>
<example>ask password &quot;Please log in.&quot; titled &quot;Millenium Group Intranet&quot;</example>
<example><p>ask password empty with savedPassword as sheet</p></example>
<example>ask password &quot;Please log in:&quot; with &quot;PASSWORD&quot; titled &quot;Password Test&quot;</example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		<changed version="6.0.0">.</changed>
		<changed version="4.6.1">Added Support for Android.</changed>
<changed version="2.0">2.0</changed>
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<web/>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Windows &amp; Dialog Boxes</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<function tag="mcEncrypt">mcEncrypt Function</function>
		<command tag="ask">ask Command</command>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>ask password</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> to provide privacy for the information the user types. For example, if the user is in a public place, the information might be seen by someone looking over his or her shoulder. This command does not <glossary tag="encrypt">encrypt</glossary> the text the user types, but you can use <b>ask password</b> to implement a secret <property tag="password">password with the syntax shown in the example section.</property>.</overview>

		<parameters>
<parameter>
<name>question</name>
<description>Is a string or any expression that evaluates to a string.</description>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<name>defaultResponse</name>
<description>Is placed in the text box when the dialog box appears. If no defaultResponse is specified, the text box is empty when the dialog box appears.</description>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<name>windowTitle</name>
<description>If specified, appears in the title bar of the dialog box. If no windowTitle is given, the title bar is blank.</description>
</parameter>		</parameters>

	<value></value>
	<comments>The text contents of the text box is placed in the <b>it</b> <glossary tag="variable">variable</glossary>. If the user cancels the <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog</glossary>, the <keyword tag="it">it</keyword> <glossary tag="variable">variable</glossary> is set to empty, and the <function tag="result">result</function> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st> <glossary tag="return">returns</glossary> &quot;cancel&quot;.<p></p><p>If the ask password clear form is used, the text box is not encrypted, and the <b>it</b> <glossary tag="variable">variable</glossary> contains whatever the user entered (this is the default behavior).</p><p></p><p>If the ask password...as sheet form is used, the dialog box appears as a sheet on OS X systems. On other systems, the as sheet form has no effect and the dialog box appears normally. Attempting to open a sheet from within another sheet displays the second <i>stack</i> as a <glossary tag="modal dialog box">modal dialog box</glossary> instead.</p><p></p><p></p><note>Android and iOS do not support 'as sheet'.</note><p></p><p></p><change><p>'ask password clear' set to the default behavior at version 6.0.0 to provide compatibility across all platforms.</change><p></p><p></p><change><p>The 'ask password...as sheet' form was introduced in version 2.0.</change></comments>
	</description>
</doc>