<doc>	<legacy_id>1442</legacy_id>	<name>beep</name>	<type>command</type>	<syntax>		<example>beep [<i>numberOfTimes</i>]</example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Sounds the system beep.</summary>	<examples><example>beep</example><example>beep 7</example><example><p>beep trunc(field &quot;Severity Level&quot;)</p></example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version="5.5">Android Support Added</changed><changed version="4.5.2">iOS Support Added</changed>	</history>	<objects>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>		<ios/>		<android/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<web/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>		<category>Images &amp; Multimedia</category>	</classification>	<references>		<command tag="play">play Command</command>		<property tag="beepDuration">beepDuration Property</property>		<property tag="beepLoudness">beepLoudness Property</property>		<property tag="beepPitch">beepPitch Property</property>		<property tag="playLoudness">playLoudness Property</property>		<property tag="beepSound">beepSound Property</property>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use the <b>beep</b> command to get the user's attention.</overview>		<parameters>  <parameter>    <name>numberOfTimes</name>    <description>An integer (or an expression that evaluates to an integer) and specifies how many beeps are sounded. If the <i>numberOfTimes</i> is not specified, one beep is sounded.</description>  </parameter>		</parameters>	<value></value>	<comments>If the <i>numberOfTimes</i> is less than 1, the <b>beep</b> command has no effect (but does not cause a <glossary tag="error">script error</glossary>).<p></p><p></p><cp_note><function tag="openStacks">Windows</function> and <glossary tag="OS X">OS X</glossary> do not <glossary tag="execute">execute</glossary> the <b>beep</b> command if it's issued while a beep is playing. This means that if you specify a <i>numberOfTimes</i> on a <function tag="openStacks">Windows</function> or <glossary tag="OS X">OS X system</glossary>, the user might hear fewer beeps because not all of them are sent to the speaker. To ensure that the user hears a specific number of beeps, use a <glossary tag="loop">loop</glossary> with a <command tag="wait">wait</command> command (where the wait time is at least as long as the beep sound's duration) after each beep:</cp_note><p></p><p></p><note>Overuse of the <b>beep</b> command has been known to cause user stress.</note><p></p><p></p><note>The iPhone has no default system alert sound so if a sound is required one must be specified using the <property tag="beepSound">beepSound</property> property. The action of <b>beep</b> is controlled by the system and depends on the user's preference settings. In particular a beep will only cause a vibration if the user has enabled that feature. Similarly, a beep will only cause a sound if the phone is not in silent mode.</note><p></p><p></p><note>Android tries to use the default NOTIFICATION sound or uses the RINGTONE sound, if the NOTIFICATION sound is not available.</note></p></comments>	</description></doc>