<doc>	<legacy_id>2345</legacy_id>	<name>combine</name>	<type>command</type>	<syntax>		<example>combine array {using | by | with} primaryDelimiter [and secondaryDelimiter]</example>		<example>combine array {using | by | with} primaryDelimiter as set</example>		<example>combine array {using | by | with} {row | column}</example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Transforms an <glossary tag="array">array</glossary> into a list. </summary>	<examples><example>combine myArray using comma</example><example>combine myArray by row</example><example><p>put "apple" into tArray[1]</p><p>put "banana" into tArray[2]</p><p>combine tArray using return and ":"</p><p>   </p><p>## RESULT tArray</p><p>## 1:apple</p><p>## 2:banana</p><p>   </p><p></p><p></p><p></p></example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="1.1">Added. </introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version="2.8.1">2.8.1</changed>		<experimental version=""></experimental>		<nonexperimental version=""></nonexperimental>	</history>	<objects>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>		<ios/>		<android/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<server/>		<web/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>		<category>Values &amp; Properties</category>	</classification>	<references>		<function tag="extents">extents Function</function>		<function tag="keys">keys Function</function>		<command tag="split">split Command</command>		<property tag="columnDelimiter">columnDelimiter Property</property>		<property tag="rowDelimiter">rowDelimiter Property</property>		<keyword tag="using">using Keyword</keyword>		<keyword tag="[]">[] Keyword</keyword>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use the <b>combine</b> command to display an array in a field or to process an array using string operators, functions, and chunk expressions. </overview>		<parameters>  <parameter>    <name>arrayName</name>    <description>An array variable.</description>  </parameter>  <parameter>    <name>primaryDelimiter</name>    <description>A character or expression that resolves to a character.</description>  </parameter>  <parameter>    <name>secondaryDelimiter</name>    <description>A character or expression that resolves to a character.</description>  </parameter>		</parameters>	<value></value>	<comments>The <b>combine</b> command combines the elements of the array into a single variable. After the command is finished executing, the variable specified by array is no longer an array. <p></p><p>If the first form of the command is used, the elements of the original array are separated by the <i>primaryDelimiter</i>. For example, if the <i>primaryDelimiter</i> is return, the content of each element of the original array appears on a separate line. </p><p></p><p>If you specify a <i>secondaryDelimiter</i>, the key corresponding to each element is added to the element's content, separated from the content by the <i>secondaryDelimiter</i>. For example, if the <i>primaryDelimiter</i> is return and the <i>secondaryDelimiter</i> is tab, each line of the resulting variable contains an element's key, a tab character, and the element's content. If you don't specify a <i>secondaryDelimiter</i>, then the keys are lost in the transformation. </p><p></p><p>If you use the as set form the <b>combine</b> command rebuilds the list using the delimiter passed, the values of the array are ignored.</p><p></p><p></p><note> The order of the elements is not alphabetical or chronological; it is based on the internal hash order of the array. To alphabetize the list, use the sort command:</note><p></p><p>  combine monthlyReceivables using return and comma</p><p>  sort lines of monthlyReceivables by item 2 of each</p><p></p><p>If the second form of the <b>combine</b> command is used, the elements of the original array are considered to be either columns or rows, separated by the <property tag="columnDelimiter">columnDelimiter property</property> or <property tag="rowDelimiter">rowDelimiter property</property> respectively.</p><p></p><p>Combining an array by row converts the array into a table with rows separated by the <property tag="rowDelimiter">rowDelimiter property</property>. Each row in the resulting string is the contents of the corresponding key in the array. </p><p></p><p>Combining an array by column converts the array into a table with columns separated by the <property tag="columnDelimiter">columnDelimiter property</property>. Each column of the resulting string is the contents of the corresponding key in the array.</p><p></p><p></p><note> The combine by row and combine by column forms can only be used with numerically keyed arrays</note><p></p><p></p><change><p>The combine by row / column form was added in 2.8.1</change></comments>	</description></doc>