<doc>
	<legacy_id>1222</legacy_id>
	<name>delete file</name>
	<type>command</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>delete file <i>pathname</i></example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
		<synonym>clear file</synonym>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Removes a <keyword tag="file">file</keyword> from the user's system.</summary>

	<examples>
<example>delete file &quot;/tmp/handlers.txt&quot;</example>
<example>delete file &quot;My Test.rev&quot;</example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		<changed version="4.6.1">Added Support for Android</changed>
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<server/>
		<web/>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
		<disk/>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Files, Folders, &amp; Resources</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<command tag="revDeleteFolder">revDeleteFolder Command</command>
		<command tag="delete">delete Command</command>
		<command tag="close file">close file Command</command>
		<command tag="delete URL">delete URL Command</command>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>delete file</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> to clean up by removing a <keyword tag="file">file</keyword> you created.</overview>

		<parameters>
<parameter>
<name>pathName</name>
<description>Specifies the name and location of the file. If you specify a name but not a location, LiveCode assumes the file is in the defaultFolder.</description>
</parameter>		</parameters>

	<value></value>
	<comments>This command can also be used to remove files your stack did not create. Of course, a stack should not remove files and folders it did not create without obtaining explicit confirmation from the user.<p></p><p>If the file do not exist, is a folder, or for some other reason cannot be deleted, the <b>result</b> is set to &quot;Can't delete that file.&quot;.</p><p></p><p><code tag=""><caution></code><code tag="">This</code> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> cannot be undone, so be very certain before you use it. The <b>delete file</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> removes the file completely from the user's system. It does not place the file in the Trash or Recycle Bin.</caution><p></p><p></p><note>iOS imposes strict controls over what you can and cannot access. Each application in iOS is stored in its own 'sandbox' folder (referred to as the home folder). An application is free to read and write files within this folder and its descendants, but it is not allowed to access anything outside of the 'sandbox'.</note><p></p><p></p><note>An Android application is installed on the phone in the form of its zip package. This means that any assets that are included are not available as discrete files in the native filesystem. In order to manage this the engine essentially 'virtualizes' the asset files you include, allowing (read-only) manipulation with all the standard LiveCode file and folder handling syntax.</note></comments>
	</description>
</doc>