<doc>
  <legacy_id>2403</legacy_id>
  <name>do</name>
  <type>command</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>do <i>statementList</i> [as a<i>lternateLanguageName</i>]</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Writing LiveCode</category>
    <category>Standalone Applications</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="call">call Command</command>
    <command tag="debugDo">debugDo Command</command>
    <command tag="local">local Command</command>
    <command tag="breakpoint">breakpoint Command</command>
    <function tag="alternateLanguages">alternateLanguages Function</function>
    <keyword tag="message box">message box Keyword</keyword>
    <keyword tag="as">as Keyword</keyword>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="2.9"></changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary><glossary tag="execute">Executes</glossary> a list of <glossary tag="statement">statements</glossary>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>do "go next card"</example>
    <example>do "put" &amp;&amp; x &amp;&amp; "into tNumberOfRecords" &amp; x <i>-- might become "put 3 into tNumberOfRecords"</i></example>
    <example>do "select" &amp;&amp; line 3 of field "Objects"</example>
    <example>do field "Statements" as AppleScript</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>do</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> to <glossary tag="execute">execute</glossary> <glossary tag="statement">statements</glossary> in a <glossary tag="container">container</glossary>, or to <glossary tag="execute">execute</glossary> a <glossary tag="statement">statement</glossary> that consists partly of a <glossary tag="literal string">literal string</glossary> and partly of a <glossary tag="container">container</glossary> or the <glossary tag="return value">return value</glossary> from a <control_st tag="function">function</control_st>.</p><p/><p><b>Parameters:</b></p><p>The <i>statementList</i> is a <glossary tag="LiveCode">LiveCode</glossary> <glossary tag="statement">statement</glossary>, a <glossary tag="container">container</glossary> with one or more <glossary tag="statement">statements</glossary>, or a <keyword tag="string">string</keyword> that <glossary tag="evaluate">evaluates</glossary> to a <glossary tag="statement">statement</glossary>.</p><p/><p>On Mac OS and OS X systems, the a<i>lternateLanguageName</i> is a script language (such as <href tag="glossary/Writing_Tr/381.xml">AppleScript</href>) supported under the <glossary tag="Open Scripting Architecture (OSA)">Open Scripting Architecture</glossary>. </p><p/><p>On Windows systems, the <i>alternateLanguageName</i> is an "active scripting" language (such as VBScript) supported by the Windows Scripting Host.</p><p/><p>The available languages are <glossary tag="return">returned</glossary> by the <function tag="alternateLanguages">alternateLanguages</function> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st>. If you specify an a<i>lternateLanguageName</i>, the <i>statementList</i> must be written in the specified language.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>Using the <b>do</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> is slower than directly <glossary tag="execute">executing</glossary> the <glossary tag="command">commands</glossary>, because each <glossary tag="statement">statement</glossary> must be <glossary tag="compile">compiled</glossary> every time the <b>do</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> is executed.</p><p/><p>On Mac OS X systems, if you use the do as a<i>lternateLanguageName</i> form, any result returned by the script language is placed in the <function tag="result">result</function>.</p><p/><p>On Windows systems, the <function tag="result">result</function> function will return the value of the global variable called "result" in the script that was executed (or empty if no such variable was defined). For example the following code will produce a dialog box containing "2":</p><p/><p>do "result = 1 + 1" as "vbscript"</p><p>answer the result</p><p/><p><img src="202653"/> <b>Important!</b> If using the do as <i>alternateLanguageName</i> form, any paths used in the <i>statementList</i> must be in the native format of the current system. In particular this means that paths must be converted to Windows native format before use on Windows machines. In most cases this can be done by replacing slash with backslash in the path.</p><p/><p>When using a standalone application created by LiveCode, you can include up to ten statements in the <i>statementList</i>. This limit is set by line 2 of the <function tag="scriptLimits">scriptLimits</function> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st>. This limitation does not apply when using the <glossary tag="development environment">development environment</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> The ten-statement limit in standalones applies only if the <i>statementList</i> is written in <glossary tag="LiveCode">LiveCode</glossary>. If you specify an <i>alternateLanguageName</i> this limit does not apply.</p><p/><p>If you attempt to specify an <i>alternateLanguageName</i> on a <glossary tag="Unix">Unix</glossary> <glossary tag="Windows">system</glossary>, the <b>do</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> is not executed, and the <function tag="result">result</function> is set to "alternate language not found".</p><p/><p>Any scripts on Windows which contain references to WScript will fail to run as WScript objects do not exist in the LiveCode Environment.  Return values should therefore be placed within the global <function tag="result">result</function> variable instead of using WScript.Echo.</p><p/><p>To see how to create a numbered set of variables see the dictionary entry for the <command tag="local">local command</command>.</p><p/><p><b>Changes:</b></p><p>The <i>alternateLanguageName</i> option was introduced in version 1.1. In previous versions, it was not possible to include <href tag="glossary/Writing_Tr/381.xml">AppleScript</href> or other <glossary tag="Open Scripting Architecture (OSA)">OSA</glossary> languages in a <glossary tag="LiveCode">LiveCode</glossary> <glossary tag="handler">handler</glossary>.</p><p/><p>The ability to specify an <i>alternateLanguageName</i> on Windows systems was added in LiveCode 2.9.</p>
  </description>
</doc>