<doc>	<legacy_id>2401</legacy_id>	<name>filter</name>	<type>command</type>	<syntax>		<example>filter [lines of | items of] <i>container</i> {with | without | [not] matching} [wildcard pattern | regex pattern] <i>filterPattern</i> [into <i>targetContainer</i>]</example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Filters each line or item in a source container or expression, removing the lines or items that do or don't match a pattern.</summary>	<examples><example>filter myVariable without "*[a-zA-Z]*"</example><example>filter items of field 22 with regex pattern "b.*"</example><example><p>filter lines of theList not matching "foo*" into theFilteredList</p></example><example>filter field "my lines" matching wildcard pattern "[" &amp; mySelection &amp; "]"</example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version="2.1.1">2.1.1</changed><changed version="6.1">6.1</changed>		<experimental version=""></experimental>		<nonexperimental version=""></nonexperimental>	</history>	<objects>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>		<ios/>		<android/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<server/>		<web/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>		<category>Text and Data Processing</category>	</classification>	<references>		<function tag="matchChunk">matchChunk Function</function>		<function tag="matchText">matchText Function</function>		<function tag="replaceText">replaceText Function</function>		<command tag="replace">replace Command</command>		<command tag="sort">sort Command</command>		<property tag="caseSensitive">caseSensitive Property</property>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use the <b>filter</b> command to pick specific lines or items in a container or expression.</overview>		<parameters><parameter><name>container</name><description>A reference to or an expression that evaluates to a container.</description></parameter><parameter><name>filterPattern</name><description>An expression used to match certain lines or items.</description></parameter>		</parameters>	<value></value>	<comments>The <b>filter</b>...with form and the <b>filter</b>...matching form retain the lines or items that contain a match for the specified <i>filterPattern</i>.<p></p><p>The <b>filter</b>...without form and the <b>filter</b>...not matching form discard the lines or items that do not contain a match for the specified <i>filterPattern</i>.</p><p></p><p>If you don't specify lines or items, all lines of the container are filtered.</p><p></p><p>If a regex pattern is specified, the <i>filterPattern</i> evaluates to a regular expression.</p><p></p><p>If a wildcard <i>filterPattern</i> is specified, the <i>filterPattern</i> consists of a string of characters to match, which may be combined with any number of the following special characters:</p><p></p><p>* - Matches zero or more of any character. The filterPattern A*C matches "AC", "ABC", or "ADZXC".</p><p>? - Matches exactly one character. The filterPattern A?C matches "ABC", but not "AC" or "ADZXC".</p><p>[chars] - Matches any one of the characters inside the brackets. The filterPattern A[BC]D matches "ABD" or "ACD", but not "AD" or "ABCD".</p><p>[char-char] - Matches any character whose ASCII value is between the first character and the second character.</p><p></p><p>If no <i>filterPattern</i> type is specified, the filterPattern is handled as a wildcard.</p><p></p><p>If no <i>targetContainer</i> is specified, and you filter a container, the container contents will be replaced by the filtered result.</p><p></p><p>If you filter a string without a <i>targetContainer</i>, the filtered string will be placed in the <keyword tag="it">it variable</keyword>.</p><p></p><p><change></p><p>The <b>filter</b>...without form was added in version 2.1.1. In previous versions, the <b>filter</b> command could be used only to retrieve lines that matched a wildcard expression.<p>The <b>filter</b> items... form was added in version 6.1. In previous versions, the <b>filter</b> command could be used only to retrieve lines.</change><p>The ability to filter using a regular expression was added in version 6.1. In previous versions, the <b>filter</b> command only supported wildcard expressions.</p><p>The ability to filter an expression was added in version 6.1. In previous versions, the <b>filter</b> command could be used only for a container.</p><p>The <b>filter</b>...[not] matching form was added in version 6.1 to clarify the pattern handling.</p><p>The <b>filter</b>...into form was added in version 6.1. In previous versions, the filter command always replaced the contents of the original container.</p></comments>	</description></doc>