<doc>	<legacy_id></legacy_id>	<name>iphoneUseDeviceResolution</name>	<type>command</type>	<syntax>		<example>iphoneUseDeviceResolution { <i>true</i> | <i>false</i> }, [true | false]</example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Sets whether the full resolution of high-resolution devices is to be used</summary>	<examples><example>iphoneUseDeviceResolution true</example><example>iphoneUseDeviceResolution true, true</example><example><p>iphoneUseDeviceResolution true, false</p></example><example>iphoneUseDeviceResolution false</example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="4.5.2">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version=""></changed>	</history>	<objects>	</objects>	<platforms>		<ios/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>	</classification>	<references>		<function tag="iphoneDeviceResolution">iphoneDeviceResolution Function</function>		<function tag="iphoneDeviceScale">iphoneDeviceScale Function</function>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use the <b>iphoneUseDeviceResolution</b> command to specify whether the full resolution of high-resolution devices should be used.</overview>		<parameters>		</parameters>	<value></value>	<comments>The <b>iphoneUseDeviceResolution</b> command specifies whether the full resolution of high-resolution devices should be used.<p></p><p>The iPhone 4 has a display with double the resolution in both horizontal and vertical directions. By default, iOS handles this by mapping one logical &apos;point&apos; to two physical &apos;pixels&apos; with applications (LiveCode included) interpreting everything in terms of logical points. This means that apps targetted for older devices can run identically on the newer iPhone 4 devices.</p><p></p><p>If the <b>iphoneUseDeviceResolution</b> command is passed <i>true</i> as the first argument, LiveCode ensures that co-ordinates and sizes specified in LiveCode are treated as being in pixels, rather than logical points. In particular, when changed, a resizeStack message is sent notifying the size change of the current main-stack, and functions and properties (such as the screenRect) reflects co-ordinates in pixels.</p><p></p><p>If the <b>iphoneUseDeviceResolution</b> command is passed <i>true</i> as the second argument, LiveCode ensures that co-ordinates and sizes specified in LiveCode for custom controls are treated as being in pixels, rather than logical points.</p><p></p><p></p><p></p><note>The notion of pixel and logical point remains valid on older devices, it is just that it is always 1-1 thus using this command has no effect there. The scale of the device&apos;s screen (relative to a non-Retina display) can be queried using iphoneDeviceScale(). This function returns 2 if the display is a Retina display, or 1 otherwise.</note></comments>	</description></doc>