<doc>
	<legacy_id></legacy_id>
	<name>mobileComposeTextMessage</name>
	<type>command</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>mobileComposeTextMessage <i>recipients, </i>[<i>body</i>]</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Opens a new text message in the user&apos;s text messaging program.</summary>

	<examples>
<example>mobileComposeTextMessage &quot;555 555 555&quot;, &quot;This is the text body&quot;</example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="5.5">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		<changed version=""></changed>
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Networks &amp; Communication</category>
		<category>Standalone Applications</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<function tag="mobileCanComposeTextMessage">mobileCanComposeTextMessage function</function>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>mobileComposeTextMessage</b> command to create a text message from within a mobile app.</overview>

		<parameters>
  <parameter>
    <name>recipients</name>
    <description>A comma delimited list of telephone numbers.</description>
  </parameter>
  <parameter>
    <name>body</name>
    <description>The body text of the message.</description>
  </parameter>		</parameters>

	<value>Upon completion of a compose request, the result is set to one of the following:<p>* sent - the text was sent (iOS only)</p><p>* cancel - the text was not sent, and the user elected not to save it for later</p><p>* failed - the text could not be sent</p><p>* false - the device does not have text messaging functionality</p></value>
	<comments>This command interfaces with the mobile text composition interface.<p></p><p>Some devices are not configured with text sending capability. To determine if the current device is capable of sending text messages, use the mobileCanComposeTextMessage function. This returns true if the text client is configured.</p><p></p><p></p><note>Once the <b>mobileComposeTextMessage</b> command is called, you have no more control over what the user does with the message. They are free to modify the message and the telephone numbers as they see fit.</note><p></p><p></p><note>On Android, the text messaging application can be a user preferred application that allows multiple text massages to be sent. LiveCode only receives <b>cancel</b>. The success of text deliveries is not returned in these cases.</note></comments>
	</description>
</doc>