<doc>	<legacy_id>1298</legacy_id>	<name>place</name>	<type>command</type>	<syntax>		<example>place <i>group</i> onto <i>card</i></example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Adds an existing group of objects to a card and sets the sharedBehavior property to true.</summary>	<examples><example>place group &quot;Navigation&quot; onto card &quot;Navy&quot; <i>-- group is on current card</i></example><example>place background 1 onto this card <i>-- group may be on any card</i></example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version="4.6.4">Updated.</changed>	</history>	<objects>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>		<ios/>		<android/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<server/>		<web/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>		<category>Objects &amp; Messages</category>	</classification>	<references>		<command tag="start editing">start editing Command</command>		<command tag="create card">create card Command</command>		<command tag="copy">copy Command</command>		<command tag="insert script">insert script Command</command>		<property tag="backgroundBehavior">backgroundBehavior Property</property>		<property tag="groupNames">groupNames Property</property>		<keyword tag="onto">onto Keyword</keyword>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use the <b>place</b> command to add an existing group to a card.</overview>		<parameters><parameters>  <parameter>    <name>group</name>    <description>The group is any group in the current stack that is not contained (nested) in another group.</description>  </parameter>  <parameter>    <name>card</name>    <description>The card is any card in the current stack.</description>  </parameter></parameters>		</parameters>	<value></value>	<comments>Only top-level groups may be placed onto multiple cards; an attempt to <b>place</b> a nested group onto another card throws an error.<p></p><p>Placing a group onto another card automatically sets the <property tag="sharedBehavior">sharedBehavior</property> property of the group to true.</p><p></p><p></p><warning>If the group did not previously have the <property tag="sharedBehavior">sharedBehavior</property> property set to true, placing a group will (in addition) set its <property tag="backgroundBehavior">backgroundBehavior</property> property to true. This is legacy behavior and will be removed in version 5.0. Scripts that rely on <b>place</b> setting <property tag="backgroundBehavior">backgroundBehavior</property> to true for new groups should be updated to explicitly do so after the <b>place</b> command.</warning><p></p><p></p><important>The words &quot;group&quot; and &quot;background&quot; are not always interchangeable. A group reference with the word &quot;group&quot; refers to a group on the current card. To refer to a group that's not on the current card, you must use the &quot;background&quot; form.</important><p></p><p></p><tip>To have a group automatically placed on newly created cards, leave its <property tag="backgroundBehavior">backgroundBehavior</property> property as true.</tip></comments>	</description></doc>