<doc>
  <legacy_id>3516</legacy_id>
  <name>revMailUnicode</name>
  <type>command</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>revMailUnicode address [, <i>ccAddress</i> [, <i>mailSubject</i> [, <i>messageBody</i>]]]</example>
  </syntax>
  <library>Common library</library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="revMail">revMail Command</command>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="3.5">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Opens a new unicode email message in the user's email program</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>revMailUnicode "help@example.com", the cUnicodeHelpSubject of me, the text of field "Message body" of me</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>revMailUnicode</b> command to create an email message from within a stack.</p><p/><p><b>Parameters:</b></p><p>The <i>address</i> is a string consisting of one or more email addresses, separated by commas. These addresses will appear in the To: header of the email message</p><p/><p>The <i>ccAddress</i> is a string consisting of one or more email addresses separated by commas. These addresses will appear in the CC: header of the email message.</p><p/><p>The <i>mailSubject</i> is a unicode string consisting of a single line. This will appear in the Subject: header of the email message.</p><p/><p>The <i>messageBody</i> is a unicode string. This text will appear in the body of the email message.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>When LiveCode executes the <b>revMailUnicode</b> command, the user's email program is opened (if necessary) and a new email message with the specified parameters is created. The user can change any of the settings before sending the message, and the message is not sent automatically: the user must explicitly send it (for example by clicking the "Send" button in the email program).</p><p/><p>On Mac OS X systems, the email message is opened in the application the user has set for the "mailto:" protocol in the system preferences.</p><p/><p>For some older email programs, it may not be possible to specify a <i>ccAddress</i>, <i>mailSubject</i> or <i>messageBody</i>. Generally the <b>revMailUnicode</b> command will still work with such programs, but only the To: header will be set.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> When included in a <glossary tag="standalone application">standalone application</glossary>, the <glossary tag="Common library">Common library</glossary> is implemented as a hidden <command tag="group">group</command> and made available when the <command tag="group">group</command> receives its first <message tag="openBackground">openBackground</message> message. During the first part of the <glossary tag="application">application's</glossary> startup process, before this <keyword tag="message box">message</keyword> is sent, the <b>revMailUnicode</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> is not yet available. This may affect attempts to use this <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> in <message tag="startup">startup</message>, <message tag="preOpenStack">preOpenStack</message>, <message tag="openStack">openStack</message>, or <message tag="preOpenCard">preOpenCard</message> <glossary tag="handler">handlers</glossary> in the <glossary tag="main stack">main stack</glossary>. Once the <glossary tag="application">application</glossary> has finished starting up, the <command tag="start using">library</command> is available and the <b>revMailUnicode</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> can be used in any <glossary tag="handler">handler</glossary>.</p><p/>
  </description>
</doc>