<doc>
  <legacy_id>1220</legacy_id>
  <name>revPrintReport</name>
  <type>command</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>revPrintReport</example>
  </syntax>
  <library>Printing library</library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Printing</category>
    <category>Standalone Applications</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="revPrintField">revPrintField Command</command>
    <command tag="revPrintText">revPrintText Command</command>
    <command tag="print">print Command</command>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
    <printing/>
  </security>
  <summary>Prints a report from the <glossary tag="report viewer">report viewers</glossary> on the <glossary tag="current card">current card</glossary>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>revPrintReport</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p><b>Note:</b> This stack is no-longer suppoted but can still be used by manually launching the tool.</p><p/><p>Use the <b>revPrintReport</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> to print a report that you have set up in the <glossary tag="Report Builder">Report Builder</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>When you use the Report Builder to create a set of report settings, the settings are stored with the card. The <b>revPrintReport</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> uses the settings specified in the <glossary tag="Report Builder">Report Builder</glossary> for the <glossary tag="current card">current card</glossary> to print the report. If you have never used the <glossary tag="Report Builder">Report Builder</glossary> with the <glossary tag="current card">current card</glossary> (and therefore there are no report settings to use), the <b>revPrintReport</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> causes a <glossary tag="error">script error</glossary>.</p><p/><p>The <b>revPrintReport</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> is equivalent to choosing Tools menu<img src="202656"/>Report Builder and clicking "Print Report".</p><p/><p><img src="202653"/> <b>Important!</b> The <b>revPrintReport</b> com is part of the Printing library. To ensure that the command works in a standalone application, you must include this custom library when you create your standalone. In the Inclusions section on the General screen of the Standalone Application Settings window, make sure that "Printing" is selected in the list of script libraries.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> When included in a standalone application, the Printing library is implemented as a hidden group and made available when the group receives its first openBackground message. During the first part of the applicati startup process, before this message is sent, the <b>revPrintReport</b> command is not yet available. This may affect attempts to use this command in startup, preOpenStack, openStack, or preOpenCard hand in the main stack. Once the application has finished starting up, the library is available and the <b>revPrintReport</b> command can be used in any handler.</p>
  </description>
</doc>