<doc>
  <legacy_id>3076</legacy_id>
  <name>revZipAddUncompressedItemWithData</name>
  <type>command</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>revZipAddUncompressedItemWithData <i>archivePath</i>, <i>itemName</i>, <i>variableName</i></example>
  </syntax>
  <library>Zip Library</library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="revZipAddItemWithData">revZipAddItemWithData Command</command>
    <command tag="revZipOpenArchive">revZipOpenArchive Command</command>
    <command tag="revZipAddUncompressedItemWithFile">revZipAddUncompressedItemWithFile Command</command>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.8.1">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
    <disk access="???"/>
    <network/>
  </security>
  <summary>Adds an item to a zip archive and puts the specified data into it without compressing the data.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>revZipAddUncompressedItemWithData tArchive, "My Uncompressed Data.txt", "This is my data"</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>revZipAddUncompressedItemWithData</b> command to put data from a LiveCode variable into a file in a zip archive without compressing the data. The archive must have first been opened with <b>revZipOpenArchive</b>. This command is useful if data is being placed into an archive simply to package it up neatly, rather than to reduce the size of the data. Using <b>revZipAddUncompressedItemWithData</b> to add items to archives is generally faster than using the <command tag="revZipAddItemWithData">revZipAddItemWithData command</command>, which compresses the data.</p><p/><p><b>Parameters:</b></p><p>The <i>archivePath</i> is the absolute path to the zip archive to add the file to. </p><p>The <i>itemName</i> is the unique name of the item to create in the zip archive.  The variableName is the name of a variable in your LiveCode program containing data to place into the item in the zip archive. </p><p/><p>If the <b>revZipAddUncompressedItemWithData</b> command encounters an error then the result will be set to an error code beginning with "ziperr", otherwise the result will be empty.</p>
  </description>
</doc>