<doc>	<legacy_id>2452</legacy_id>	<name>rotate</name>	<type>command</type>	<syntax>		<example>rotate [<i>image</i>] by <i>numberOfDegrees</i></example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Rotates an <keyword tag="image">image</keyword> through the specified angle.</summary>	<examples><example>rotate by 90</example><example>rotate image &quot;Spinner&quot; by -10</example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="1.1">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version="3.0">3.0</changed>	</history>	<objects>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>	</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<server/>		<web/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>	</security>	<classification>		<category>Images  Multimedia</category>		<category>Appearance  Positioning</category>	</classification>	<references>		<command tag="revRotatePoly">revRotatePoly Command</command>		<command tag="crop">crop Command</command>		<command tag="choose">choose Command</command>	</references>	<description>Use the <b>rotate</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> to turn an <keyword tag="image">image</keyword>.<p></p><p><b>Parameters:</b></p><p>The <i>image</i> is any image reference.</p><p></p><p>The <i>numberOfDegrees</i> is a number, or an <glossary tag="expression">expression</glossary> that <glossary tag="evaluate">evaluates</glossary> to a number.</p><p></p><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The entire content of the specified image is selected with the Select paint tool, then rotated. If you don't specify an <i>image</i>, the portion currently selected with the Select <glossary tag="paint tool">paint tool</glossary> is rotated.</p><p></p><p>If the <i>numberOfDegrees</i> is positive, the image rotates counterclockwise. If the <i>numberOfDegrees</i> is negative, the image rotates clockwise.</p><p></p><p>If the rotated image extends beyond the boundaries of the original image, and the image's <b>lockLocation</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is set to false, the <keyword tag="image">image</keyword> expands to accommodate the rotated contents. If the <property tag="lockLocation">lockLocation</property> is true, the rotated <keyword tag="image">image</keyword> is cropped to fit within the <glossary tag="image">image's</glossary> <keyword tag="rectangle">rectangle</keyword>.</p><p></p><p>The current setting of the <property tag="resizeQuality">resizeQuality property</property> is used to determine whether to apply filtering to the rotation operation. If set to normal no filtering is used; if set to good or best a bilinear filter is used which significantly reduces the distortion that will naturally occur when an image is rotated.</p><p></p><p>The rotation operation does not have an inverse. Since some amount of distortion is unavoidable when rotating an image by an amount that is not a multiple of 90 degrees, rotating an image clockwise, then counterclockwise by the same amount does not completely restore the original image.</p><p></p><p>To rotate an image in a reversible way, or to do repeated rotations without progressive distortion of the image, set its <b>angle</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> instead of using the <b>rotate</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary>. Unlike the <b>rotate</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary>, the <property tag="angle">angle</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> affects only the screen display of the <keyword tag="image">image</keyword>, not the actual picture data in it, so setting it repeatedly does not introduce distortion.</p><p></p><p><b> Note:</b>Rotating an image using good or best <property tag="resizeQuality">resizeQuality</property> might cause the mask to be promoted to an alpha channel.</p><p></p><p></p><note>As rotate is an image editing operation, the target image needs to be on the currently visible card of an open stack to function.</note><p></p><p></p><important>The <b>rotate </b><glossary tag="command">command</glossary> cannot be used on a <glossary tag="referenced control">referenced image</glossary>. Doing so will cause an <glossary tag="execution error">execution error</glossary>. To turn a <glossary tag="referenced control">referenced image</glossary>, set the <glossary tag="image">image's</glossary><property tag="angle">angle </property><glossary tag="property">property</glossary> instead.</important></description></doc>