<doc>	<legacy_id></legacy_id>	<name>secure socket</name>	<type>command</type>	<syntax>		<example>secure socket <i>socket</i> [without verification]</example>		<example>secure socket <i>socket</i> [with verification [for host verificationHostName]]</example>	</syntax>	<synonyms>	</synonyms>	<summary>Secures an open socket.</summary>	<examples><example>secure socket "livecode.com:443"</example><example>open socket to "127.0.0.0:8080"write "unencrypted message" to socket "127.0.0.0:8080"secure socket "127.0.0.0:8080"write "encrypted message" to socket "127.0.0.0:8080"</example><example>secure socket mySocket with verifcation for host "livecode.com"</example>	</examples>	<history>		<introduced version="6.6">Added.</introduced>		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>		<removed version=""></removed>		<changed version="6.7">Added verification for host variant</changed>		<experimental version=""></experimental>		<nonexperimental version=""></nonexperimental>	</history>	<objects>	</objects>	<platforms>		<mac/>		<windows/>		<linux/>		<ios/>		<android/>			</platforms>	<classes>		<desktop/>		<mobile/>	</classes>	<security>		<network/>	</security>	<classification>		<category>Files, Folders, &amp; Resources</category>		<category>Standalone Applications</category>	</classification>	<references>		<command tag="open socket">open socket Command</command>		<property tag="sslCertificates">sslCertificates Property</property>		<message tag="socketError">socketError Message</message>	</references>	<description>	<overview>Use the <b>secure socket </b>command to secure an open socket.</overview>		<parameters>  <parameter>    <name>socket</name>    <description>A reference to an open socket.</description>  </parameter>  <parameter>    <name>verificationHostName</name>    <description>The IP address or domain name of the host you want to verify against.</description>  </parameter>		</parameters>	<value></value>	<comments>If 'with verification' is specified, when connecting to a remote peer, the client verifies the peers certificate during the handshake process. The <property tag="sslCertificates">sslCertificates property</property> can be used to specify a list of certificates to verify against. In addition you can place system wide certificates in System/Library/OpenSSL/certs. If a verificationhostname is specified, the socket will be verified against that verificationhostname. An example of this is when you want to create a secure connection with a host while tunnelling through a proxy. Specifying the final host allows LiveCode to verify the socket against that host, rather than the proxy server.<p></p><p>If 'without verification' is specified then peers credentials are not authenticated, and any connection is accepted.</p><p></p><p>Once secured:</p><p>* All pending and future reads from the socket will be assumed to be encrypted.</p><p>* All pending writes will complete unencrypted. All future writes will be encrypted.</p><p></p><p>If the socket fails secure, a <message tag="socketError">socketError message</message> is sent to the object that opened the socket (not the object that attempted to secure it).</p><p></p><p></p><important> The secure secure socket command is part of the SSL &amp; Encryption library. To ensure that the command works in a standalone application, you must include this custom library when you create your standalone. In the Inclusions section on the General screen of the Standalone Application Settings window, make sure "SSL &amp; Encryption" is selected in the list of script libraries.</important><p>&#9;</p></comments>	</description></doc>