<doc>
  <legacy_id>1248</legacy_id>
  <name>send to program</name>
  <type>command</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>send <i>message</i> to {program | application} <i>programAddress</i> \  [with <i>classID</i>] [{with | without} reply]</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>The System Environment</category>
    <category>Networks &amp; Communication</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <property tag="address">address Property</property>
    <message tag="appleEvent">appleEvent Message</message>
    <command tag="reply">reply Command</command>
    <command tag="request appleEvent">request appleEvent Command</command>
    <command tag="request">request Command</command>
    <keyword tag="without">without Keyword</keyword>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Sends an <glossary tag="Apple Event">Apple event</glossary> to a program.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>send "get field 3" to program "Corporate Zone:Other Mac:LiveCode"</example>
    <example>send thisMessage to application "FileMaker" without reply</example>
    <example>send field ID 9 to program someProgram with "GURLGURL"</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>send to program</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> to cause another application to take some action via the <code>dosc</code> <glossary tag="Apple Event">Apple event</glossary> or another <glossary tag="Apple Event">Apple event</glossary> you specify.</p><p/><p><b>Parameters:</b></p><p>The <i>message</i> is the message you want the other application to <glossary tag="execute">execute</glossary> (the data attached to the <glossary tag="Apple Event">Apple event</glossary> you are sending). Its exact <function tag="format">format</function> and meaning depends on the other application.</p><p/><p>The <i>programAddress</i> is the AppleTalk address of the other program. The AppleTalk address consists of three parts, separated by colons: the zone the other computer is in, the name of the computer, and the name of the target program. If the other computer is in the same zone as yours, you can omit the zone. If the other program is running on the same computer, you can omit both the zone and the computer name.</p><p/><p>The <i>classID</i> is a string consisting of the 4-character <glossary tag="Apple Event">Apple event</glossary> class and the 4-<keyword tag="character">character</keyword> event ID. If you don't specify a <i>classID</i>, LiveCode uses "<code>miscdosc</code>": the<code> misc </code>class and the<code>dosc</code> <glossary tag="event">event</glossary>.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>If the program supports the Apple event, it performs the command. If the program sends back a response, it is placed in the <b>result</b> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st>.</p><p/><p>The<code> to application </code>and<code> to program </code>forms are synonyms.</p><p/><p>If you specify the<code> with reply </code>form, the handler pauses until the application sends back a response. If you specify the<code> without reply </code>form, the handler continues immediately without waiting. If you don't specify either form, the<code> with reply </code>form is used.</p><p/><p><code/><img src="202651"/> <b>Tip:</b><code/> To display the process browser <glossary tag="dialog box">dialog box</glossary> and allow the user to choose a running program, use the following <glossary tag="statement">statement</glossary>:</p><p/><p><code>  do "choose application" as AppleScript</code></p><p/><p>For more information about Apple events, see Apple Computer's technical documentation, <i>Inside Macintosh: Interapplication Communication</i>, located at &lt;<u>http://developer.apple.com/techpubs/mac/IAC/IAC-2.html</u>&gt;.</p>
  </description>
</doc>