<doc>
  <legacy_id>1152</legacy_id>
  <name>show taskbar</name>
  <type>command</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>show taskbar</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>The System Environment</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <command tag="hide taskbar">hide taskbar Command</command>
    <command tag="show">show Command</command>
    <command tag="show menubar">show menubar Command</command>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="2.1">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="5.5.3"></changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <windows/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Displays the <glossary tag="task bar">task bar</glossary> on <glossary tag="Windows">Windows systems</glossary>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>show taskbar</example>
    <example>if the controlKey is down then show taskbar</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>show taskbar</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> to display the <glossary tag="task bar">task bar</glossary> if it has been hidden. For example, if the <glossary tag="task bar">task bar</glossary> is hidden, you might want to show it only if the user holds down the Control key.</p><p/><p>
    
    The <b>show taskbar</b> <glossary tag="command">command</glossary> can produce unexpected result when used in conjunction with <property tag="backdrop">backdrop</property> operations. The following syntax is supported:</p><p/><p>
    
      hide taskbar</p><p>
      set the backdrop to "red" -- or whatever you want</p><p/><p>
      
    This is the case where the <property tag="backdrop">backdrop</property> is visible but the taskbar is hidden when the application is active.
    After these two commands, the taskbar is hidden for the LiveCode application, the backdrop fills the screen and the taskbar reappears when switching to other applications.</p><p/><p>

    Functionality that is partially functional, due to the lack of operating system support and works sufficiently well for restricted applications is as follows:</p><p/><p>
    If the taskbar is visible before showing the backdrop, the backdrop occupies the 'working rect' of the screen, or almost the working rect of the screen if the taskbar is set to auto-hide. In the latter case, a small gap is left at the bottom of the backdrop to ensure the taskbar can still pop up when the mouse is moved to the edge of the screen.
    
    </p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The task bar can be hidden only on Windows systems. This command has no effect on Mac OS, OS X, or Unix systems.</p>
  </description>
</doc>