<doc>
	<legacy_id>1461</legacy_id>
	<name>fontNames</name>
	<type>function</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>the fontNames</example>
		<example>fontNames ([printer])</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary><glossary tag="return">Returns</glossary> a list of the currently installed <glossary tag="font">fonts</glossary>.</summary>

	<examples>
<example>the fontNames</example>
<example>fontNames ()</example>
<example><p>fontNames (printer)</p></example>
<example><p>if &quot;Monaco&quot; is among the lines of the fontNames \</p><p>  then set the textFont of me to &quot;Monaco&quot;</p></example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		<changed version="5.5">Added Support for Android</changed>
<changed version="4.5.2">Added Support for iOS.</changed>
<changed version="2.0">2.0</changed>
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<server/>
		<web/>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Appearance &amp; Positioning</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<function tag="fontStyles">fontStyles Function</function>
		<command tag="revFontLoad">revFontLoad Command</command>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>fontNames</b> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st> to find out whether a particular <glossary tag="font">font</glossary> is available before using it, or to display a list of <glossary tag="font">fonts</glossary>.</overview>

		<parameters>
		</parameters>

	<value>The <b>fontNames</b> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st> <glossary tag="return">returns</glossary> a list of <glossary tag="font">font</glossary> names, one per <keyword tag="line">line</keyword>.</value>
	<comments>The <b>fontNames </b>(printer) form returns the names of fonts available on the currently selected printer. Use this form when printing on a printer with its own resident fonts (such as a Postscript printer) to ensure that the fonts you're using are available on the printer.<p></p><p>If you do not specify 'printer', the fonts installed on the system and available to the application for screen display are listed.</p><p></p><p>In Android, iOS 3.2 and later it is possible to bundle custom fonts with an application, that only that application can use. To take advantage of this feature, you need to reference the files of any fonts you wish to include in the 'Copy Files' pane. These files can either be a direct file references, or contained in one of the folder references. The 'Standalone Builder' treats any files that end with the extension '.ttf' or '.ttc' as font files to use in this way. Any fonts included in this way appear in the <b>fontNames</b> and can be used in the same way as any other font on the system.</p><p></p><p></p><important>Make sure you have an appropriate license for the fonts you choose to bundle with your iOS app like you would any other media such as sounds, images and videos.</important><p></p><p></p><change><p>The <b>fontNames </b>() form was introduced to iOS in version 4.5.3.</change><p>The <b>fontNames </b>(printer) form was introduced in version 2.0.</p></comments>
	</description>
</doc>