<doc>
	<legacy_id></legacy_id>
	<name>mobileCurrentLocation</name>
	<type>function</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>mobileCurrentLocation()</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
		<synonym>iphoneCurrentLocation()</synonym>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Returns the current location of the device.</summary>

	<examples>
<example>put mobileCurrentLocation() into theLocation</example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="4.5.2">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		<changed version="5.5">Android support added</changed>
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>Sensors</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<function tag="mobileSensorReading">mobileSensorReading Function</function>
		<command tag="mobileStartTrackingSensor">mobileStartTrackingSensor Command</command>
		<command tag="mobileStopTrackingSensor">mobileStopTrackingSensor Command</command>
		<message tag="locationChanged">locationChanged Message</message>
		<message tag="trackingError">trackingError Message</message>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Use the <b>mobileCurrentLocation</b> function to find the current location of the device.</overview>

		<parameters>
		</parameters>

	<value>If location tracking has been enabled the <b>mobileCurrentLocation</b> function returns an array with the following keys<p>&#9;* <i>horizontal accuracy</i> - the maximum error in meters of the position indicated by longitude and latitude</p><p>&#9;* <i>latitude</i> - the latitude of the current location, measured in degrees relative to the equator. Positive values indicate positions in the Northern Hemisphere, negative values in the Southern.</p><p>&#9;* <i>longitude</i> - the longitude of the current location, measured in degrees relative to the zero meridian. Positive values extend east of the meridian, negative values extend west.</p><p>&#9;* <i>vertical accuracy</i> - the maximum error in meters of the altitude value.</p><p>&#9;* <i>altitude</i> - the distance in meters of the height of the device relative to sea-level. Positive values extend upward of sea-level, negative values downward.</p><p>&#9;* <i>timestamp</i> - the time at which the measurement was taken, in seconds since 1970.</p><p></p><p>If the <i>latitude</i> and <i>longitude</i> could not be measured, those keys together with the <i>horizontal accuracy </i>key will not be present. If the <i>altitude</i> could not be measured, that key together with the <i>vertical accuracy</i> will not be present.</p><p></p><p>If location tracking has not been enabled the <b>mobileCurrentLocation</b> function returns empty.</p></value>
	<comments>Use the <b>mobileCurrentLocation</b> function to find the current location of the device. If location tracking has not been enabled this function returns empty. Otherwise it returns an array.</comments>
	</description>
</doc>