<doc>
  <legacy_id>3520</legacy_id>
  <name>revBrowserCallScript</name>
  <type>function</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>revBrowserCallScript(<i>instanceId</i>, <i>functionName</i> [, <i>parameter1</i>, <i>parameter2</i>, ..., <i>parameterN </i>])</example>
  </syntax>
  <library>Browser Library</library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <function tag="revBrowserExecuteScript">revBrowserExecuteScript Function</function>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="3.5">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
  </classes>
  <security>
    <network/>
  </security>
  <summary>Calls a web script function in the current browser object</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>get revBrowserCallScript(sBrowserId, "swapImages")</example>
    <example>get revBrowserCallscript(sBrowserId, "displayTable", tHeader, tFooter)</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>revBrowserCallScript</b> function to call a web script function in the context of the current document in the specified browser object.</p><p/><p><b>Parameters:</b></p><p>The <i>instanceId</i> is the integer identifier of a browser object</p><p>The <i>functionName</i> is the name of the web script function to call</p><p>The parameters <i>parameter1</i>  through to <i>parameterN</i>  contain the arguments to pass to the function (optional).</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The <b>revBrowserCallScript</b> function currently searches for and calls JScript functions on Windows and JavaScript functions on OS X. If the function is not found or calling it is not successful, then an "error in script" exception is thrown.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> that the arguments passed to the function are internally treated as NULL-terminated strings. This means that binary data cannot be passed, it must first be encoded somehow. This is typically done using the <function tag="base64Encode">base64Encode function</function>.</p><p/><p>If you want to execute some arbitrary JavaScript, rather than call an existing function, use the <function tag="revBrowserExecuteScript">revBrowserExecuteScript function</function> instead. </p><p/><p>The <b>revBrowserCallScript</b> function will return whatever the function called returned.</p><p/><p><b>Note:</b> For general information on using the browser library, please see the notes in the <function tag="revBrowserOpen">revBrowserOpen function</function> reference.</p>
  </description>
</doc>