<doc>
  <legacy_id>2495</legacy_id>
  <name>weekdayNames</name>
  <type>function</type>
  <syntax>
    <example>the [long| abbr[rev[iated]] |short] [english|system|internet] weekdayNames</example>
    <example>the [internet] [english | system] weekdayNames</example>
    <example>weekdayNames()</example>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Math, Logic, &amp; Dates</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <function tag="dateFormat">dateFormat Function</function>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.1">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary><glossary tag="return">Returns</glossary> a list of names of the days of the week used by the <function tag="date">date function</function>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>put the weekdayNames into field "Weekdays"</example>
    <example>if it is not among the lines of the system weekdayNames then beep</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>weekdayNames</b> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st> to let the user choose from a list of weekday names, or to display a list of days in the language of the user's system preferences.</p><p/><p><b>Value:</b></p><p>The <b>weekdayNames</b> <control_st tag="function">function</control_st> returns a set of seven day names, one per line.</p><p/><p>The weekdayNames form returns the full name of each day, as used in the long date.</p><p/><p>The long weekdayNames form returns the same result as the weekdayNames form.</p><p/><p>The abbreviated weekdayNames form returns the first three letters of the name of each day, as used in the abbreviated date.</p><p/><p>The short weekdayNames form returns the number of each day, as used in the short date.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>For each form of the <b>weekdayNames</b>, if the <property tag="useSystemDate">useSystemDate</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> is set to true, or if you specify the system weekdayNames, the list of names is provided in the language specified by the user's system preferences. If the <b>useSystemDate</b> is false or you specify the english weekdayNames, the list of names is provided in English.</p>
  </description>
</doc>