<doc>
  <legacy_id>2128</legacy_id>
  <name>return</name>
  <type>constant</type>
  <syntax>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
    <synonym>CR</synonym>
    <synonym>linefeed</synonym>
    <synonym>LF</synonym>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Text and Data Processing</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <constant tag="formfeed">formfeed Constant</constant>
    <constant tag="CRLF">CRLF Constant</constant>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
    <changed version="2.0"></changed>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
    <ios/>
    <android/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
    <mobile/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>Equivalent to the line feed <keyword tag="character">character</keyword> (ASCII 10, Control-J).</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>put return after word 2 of theData</example>
    <example>repeat until thisChar is return</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>return</b> <command tag="constant">constant</command> as an easier-to-read substitute for<code> numToChar(10)</code>.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>The <b>return</b> <command tag="constant">constant</command> is needed because you can't type the <keyword tag="character">character</keyword> it represents in a <property tag="script">script</property>.</p><p/><p>The <b>return</b> <command tag="constant">constant</command> is a synonym for <b>linefeed</b>. This is different from some other languages, in which <b>return</b> is equivalent to the carriage return <keyword tag="character">character</keyword> (ASCII 13, Control-M). For most purposes, Revoluton translates the <b>linefeed</b> <command tag="constant">constant</command> and its synonyms into the appropriate end-of-line <keyword tag="character">character</keyword> for the current operating system. However, you should keep this nuance in mind when processing data from another system, which LiveCode has not translated:  <b>return</b> is not <glossary tag="ASCII">ASCII</glossary> 13.</p><p/><p>The line feed character is the standard end-of-line delimiter on Unix systems. The end-of-line delimiter for Mac OS systems is a carriage return, and the end-of-line delimiter for Windows systems is a carriage return followed by a line feed. Internally, LiveCode always uses a line feed to end lines.</p><p/><p><code/><b>Note:</b><code/> If you specify<code> text </code>mode with the <b>open driver</b>, <command tag="open file">open file</command>, or <command tag="open process">open process</command> <glossary tag="command">commands</glossary>, LiveCode translates line feed <keyword tag="characters">characters</keyword> to the appropriate end-of-line marker for the current <function tag="platform">platform</function> before writing data, and translates the current <glossary tag="platform">platform's</glossary> end-of-line <glossary tag="delimiter">delimiter</glossary> to a line feed after reading data. If you specify<code> binary </code>mode with these commands, LiveCode does not perform this automatic translation. Likewise, if you put data into a <keyword tag="file">file</keyword> <keyword tag="URL">URL</keyword> or get data from it, end-of-line translation is performed, but not if you put data into or get data from a <keyword tag="binfile">binfile</keyword> <keyword tag="URL">URL</keyword>.</p><p/><p><b>Changes:</b></p><p>The <b>LF</b> synonym was added in version 2.0.</p>
  </description>
</doc>