<doc>
	<legacy_id></legacy_id>
	<name>textChanged</name>
	<type>message</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>textChanged</example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Sent when the content of a field has changed.</summary>

	<examples>
<example><p>on textChanged -- <i>enable the save button when a change is made</i></p><p>   enable button &quot;save&quot;</p><p>end textChanged</p></example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="5.5">Added</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
	</history>

	<objects>
		<iosTextInput/>
		<androidTextInput/>
		<androidMultiline/>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<mac/>
		<windows/>
		<linux/>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
		<mobile/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<message tag="inputTextChanged">inputTextChanged Message</message>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Is dispatched by the field whenever a user (or simulated user) action causes the content of the field to change.</overview>

		<parameters>
		</parameters>

	<value></value>
	<comments>Handle the <b>textChanged</b> message if you want to perform an action when the content of a field changes.<p></p>The message is sent immediately after the input operation completes, but before a screen update is requested. The corresponding update occurs at the end of the first command in the <b>textChanged</b> handler. This means that you can lock the screen at the first line of the handler to delay the screen update (allowing you to modify the content of the field without any flicker).<p></p>To prevent potential for infinite recursion, calls to <b>textChanged</b> do not nest. Once a <b>textChanged</b> handler is being executed for a given field, another <b>textChanged</b> message is not sent to it, should a subsequent one be triggered.<p></p>
	The <b>textChanged</b> message is sent after messages such as keyDown and pasteKey but before messages such as keyUp.</p></comments>
	</description>
</doc>