<doc>
	<legacy_id></legacy_id>
	<name>touchRelease</name>
	<type>message</type>

	<syntax>
		<example>touchRelease  <i>touchID</i></example>
	</syntax>

	<synonyms>
	</synonyms>

	<summary>Sent when a touch sequence is cancelled due to an incoming even such as a phone-call.</summary>

	<examples>
<example><p>on touchRelease tID</p><p>  resetScreen</p><p>end touchRelease</p></example>
	</examples>

	<history>
		<introduced version="4.5.2">Added.</introduced>
		<deprecated version=""></deprecated>
		<removed version=""></removed>
		
	</history>

	<objects>
	</objects>

	<platforms>
		<ios/>
		<android/>
	</platforms>

	<classes>
		<desktop/>
	</classes>

	<security>
	</security>


	<classification>
		<category>User Interaction</category>
	</classification>

	<references>
		<message tag="touchStart">touchStart Message</message>
		<message tag="touchMove">touchMove Message</message>
		<message tag="touchEnd">touchEnd Message</message>
	</references>

	<description>
	<overview>Handle the <b>touchRelease</b> message to perform and action when a touch sequence is cancelled due to an incoming event such as a phone-call.</overview>

		<parameters>
		<parameter>The <i>touchID</i> is a number which uniquely identifies a sequence of touch messages corresponding to an individual, physical touch action</parameter>
		</parameters>

	<value></value>
	<comments>The <b>touchRelease</b> message is sent to the control which received the <message tag="touchStart">touchStart</message> message which began the touch sequence.<p></p><p>A <b>touchRelease</b> message is sent instead of a <message tag="touchEnd">touchEnd</message> message if the touch is cancelled due to an incoming event such as a phone-call.</p><p></p><p>The id parameter is a number which uniquely identifies a sequence of touch messages corresponding to an individual, physical touch action. All such sequences start with a <message tag="touchStart">touchStart</message> message, have one or more <message tag="touchMove">touchMove</message> messages and finish with either a <message tag="touchEnd">touchEnd</message> or a <b>touchRelease</b> message.</p><p></p><p>No two touch sequences will have the same id, and it is possible to have multiple (interleaving) such sequences occurring at once. This allows handling of more than one physical touch at once and, for example, allows you to track two fingers moving on the iPhone's screen.</p><p></p><p>The sequence of touch messages is tied to the control in which the touch started, in much the same way mouse messages are tied to the object a mouse down starts in. The test used to determine what object a touch starts in is identical to that used to determine whether the pointer is inside a control. In particular, invisible and disabled controls are not considered viable candidates.</p></comments>
	</description>
</doc>