<doc>
  <legacy_id>1064</legacy_id>
  <name>player</name>
  <type>object</type>
  <syntax>
  </syntax>
  <library></library>
  <objects>
  </objects>
  <synonyms>
  </synonyms>
  <classification>
    <category>Objects &amp; Messages</category>
  </classification>
  <references>
    <keyword tag="templatePlayer">templatePlayer Keyword</keyword>
    <property tag="qtIdleRate">qtIdleRate Property</property>
  </references>
  <history>
    <introduced version="1.0">Added.</introduced>
  </history>
  <platforms>
    <mac/>
    <windows/>
    <linux/>
  </platforms>
  <classes>
    <desktop/>
    <server/>
    <web/>
  </classes>
  <security>
  </security>
  <summary>A <keyword tag="control">control</keyword> that displays a movie or sound <keyword tag="file">file</keyword>.</summary>
  <examples>
    <example>start player "San Antone"</example>
    <example>hide player (the selectedText of button "Current Movie")</example>
  </examples>
  <description>
    <p>Use the <b>player</b> <glossary tag="object type">object type</glossary> to display a movie or sound from a separate <keyword tag="file">file</keyword>.</p><p/><p><b>Comments:</b></p><p>Unlike an audio clip or video clip, a player does not contain the movie or sound data. Instead, you use the player's <b>filename</b> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary> to indicate the separate <keyword tag="file">file</keyword> that holds the movie or sound. This reduces the memory required by your <object tag="stack">stack</object>, because the movie or sound data is only <glossary tag="loaded into memory">loaded into memory</glossary> when it's being used, rather than being <glossary tag="loaded into memory">loaded into memory</glossary> whenever the <glossary tag="stack file">stack file</glossary> is open. However, it also makes it possible for the movie or sound data to be misplaced during distribution, since the <keyword tag="file">file</keyword> is separate from your <glossary tag="stack file">stack file</glossary>.</p><p/><p>A player is contained in a card, group, or background. Players cannot contain other objects.</p><p/><p>The player object has a number of properties and messages associated with it. To see a list of messages that can be sent to a player as a result of user actions or internal LiveCode events, open the "LiveCode Language Dictionary" page of the main Documentation window, ensure that the player column is visible and use sort and filter to bring the relevant entries to the top.</p><p/><p><img src="202653"/> <b>Important!</b> Setting a <glossary tag="player">player's</glossary> <b>filename</b> does not automatically update its <property tag="currentTime">currentTime</property> <glossary tag="property">property</glossary>. If you play a <glossary tag="movie">movie file</glossary>, then change the <glossary tag="player">player's</glossary> <property tag="filename">filename</property> in order to play another, you must reset the <property tag="currentTime">currentTime</property> to zero in order to start from the beginning of the second <function tag="movie">movie</function>:</p><p/><p>  set the filename of player "My Player" to "SecondMovie.mov"</p><p>  set the currentTime of player "My Player" to zero</p>
  </description>
</doc>